How you doing, Keaton?
I can't feel my legs
Keyser.
Ready?
What time is it?
12:30.
It all started back in New York
six weeks ago.
A truck loaded with stripped gun parts
got jacked outside of Queens.
The driver didn't see anybody,
but somebody fucked up.
He heard a voice.
Sometimes that's all you need.
- Mr. McManus?
- Christ!
Don't you fucking guys ever sleep?
- We have a warrant for your arrest.
- Fuck you, pig.
Todd Hockney?
- Who wants to know?
- New York Police Department.
- Shit.
- Freeze!
Hold it!
Sure you brought enough guys?
It's quite simple, really.
A restaurant that changes with the taste
without losing the overall aesthetic.
In other words,
the atmosphere will not be
painted on the walls.
- Well, let me give you an example.
- This I had to see for myself.
David.
- I'm in a meeting.
- Time for another one.
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
Special Agent Kujan, US Customs.
These gentlemen are
from the New York Police Department.
You look good, Keaton.
Better than I would have thought.
A small matter of a stolen truck
loaded with guns.
Mr. Keaton?
Will you excuse us for a moment?
We have some questions
to ask you downtown.
You're gonna be a while.
No, no, no. Please, please, please.
Sit down.
This is... This is a small problem.
Enjoy the meal. I'll talk to you later.
It didn't make
sense that I'd be there.
I mean, these guys were
hard-core hijackers,
but there I was.
At that point, I wasn't scared.
I knew I hadn't done anything
they could do me for.
Besides, it was fun.
I got to make like I was notorious.
All right,
you all know the drill.
When your number is called,
step forward and repeat the phrase
you've been given. Understand?
Number one, step forward.
"Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker."
Number two, step forward.
Give me the fucking keys,
you fucking cocksucker, motherfucker!
Knock it off! Get back!
Number three, step forward.
- "Hand me the keys, you cocksucker."
In English, please.
- Excuse me'?
- In English.
Hand me the fucking keys, you cocksucker.
What the fuck?
Number four, step forward.
It was bullshit.
The whole rap was a setup.
"Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker."
It was the cops' fault.
You don't put guys like that
into a room together.
Number five, step forward.
Who knows what can happen?
"Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker."
This has really got to be
embarrassing for you guys, huh?
They drilled us all night.
Somebody was pissed
about that truck getting hijacked
and the cops had nothing.
They were hoping
somebody would slip up
and give them something to go on.
They knew we wouldn't fight it
because they knew how to lean on us.
They've been doing it forever.
I mean, our rights
went right out the window.
It was a violation. I mean, disgraceful.
They went after McManus first.
Top-notch entry man.
What truck?
The truck with the guns, fucko.
"Fucko?"
He was a good guy.
Crazy, though.
You wanna know
what your buddy Fenster told us?
- Say who?
- McManus.
He told us another story altogether.
Oh, is that the one
about the hooker with dysentery?
Fenster always worked
with McManus. He was a real tight-ass,
but when it came to the job,
he was right on. A smart man.
- What are you saying?
- I said he'll flip you.
- He'll what?
- Flip you. Flip you for real.
- Yeah, I'm shaking. Come on.
- Okay.
- Answer my question.
- Can you hear me in the back?
Hello?
I want my lawyer.
I'm gonna have your
fucking badge, cocksucker.
Todd Hockney,
good with explosives.
Without a doubt, the one guy
who didn't give a fuck about anybody.
You guys don't have
a fucking leg to stand on.
You think so, tough guy?
I can put you in Queens
on the night of the hijacking.
Really?
I live in Queens.
Did you put that together
yourself, Einstein?
What, you got a team of monkeys
working around the clock on this?
You know what happens
if you do another turn in the joint?
Fuck your father in the shower
and then have a snack.
- Are you gonna charge me, dickhead?
- I'll charge you when I'm ready.
With what?
You know damn well, dead man.
But Keaton?
Keaton was the real prize for them,
for obvious reasons.
It was your mistake, not mine.
Did you ever stop to ask me?
I mean, I've been walking around
with the same face, the same name.
I'm a businessman.
Yeah, what's that?
The restaurant business?
No. From now on, you're in
the getting-fucked-by-us business.
I'm gonna make you famous, cocksucker.
Like I said,
it was your mistake,
not mine.
Now, you charge me with this shit
and I'll beat it.
Okay?
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
All right, really, really, really,
somebody gotta do
something about this shit,
getting hauled in every five minutes.
So I did a little time.
Does that mean I get railed every time
a truck finds its way off the planet?
Fuck 'em.
Fenster, will you relax?
These guys don't have
any probable cause.
You're fucking-A right. No PC.
Not goddamn right.
You do some time, never let you go.
You know, they treat me like a criminal,
- I'll end up a criminal.
- You are a criminal.
Now, Why'd you got to go and do that?
- Trying to make a point.
- Well, why don't you make your point?
You're making me tired all over.
Oh, fuck it, then.
- I heard you were dead.
- Oh, yeah?
Well, you heard right.
Word I got is you
hung up your spurs, man.
- What's that all about?
- What's this?
Rumor has it Keaton's gone straight.
I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran.
Who is that?
She's a heavyweight criminal lawyer
from uptown.
I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
How about it, Keaton?
You a lawyer's wife?
What kind of retainer you giving her?
Whoops!
Hey, Fenster, do your friend a favor.
Tell him to keep quiet.
Dean Keaton.
Gone clean, huh?
Say it ain't so.
- Or was it you that hit that truck?
- Mac, Mac, forget him.
Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
This whole thing was a shakedown.
- What makes you say that?
- How many times you been in a lineup?
It's always you and four dummies.
The PD are paying homeless guys
10 bucks a head, half the time.
And there's no way
they'd line five felons in the same row.
No way. And what's a voice lineup?
A public defender
could get you out of that one.
- So, why the hell was I strip-searched?
- It was the feds.
A truckload of guns gets snagged,
Customs comes down on top of NYPD
looking for answers.
They come up with us.
They're clutching at straws.
I had a guy's finger up my asshole tonight.
Is it Friday already?
Yeah, lover boy.
You want a piece? Jump in. I'll love you.
So who in the goddamn piss hell
stole that fucking truck?
- What did you say?
- Who stole the fucking truck?
- I don't want to know.
- Who asked you, working man?
Fuck who did it.
What I want to know is, who's the gimp?
- He's okay.
- Says you. How do I know that?
What about it, pretzel man?
What's your story?
His name is Verbal.
Verbal Kint.
- Verbal?
- Yeah.
Roger, really. People say I talk too much.
Yeah, I was just going
to tell you to shut up.
- We met before, once or twice.
- In County. I was in for fraud.
You were in a lineup then, too.
What happened?
I walked. 90 days, suspended.
- So you did it.
- All right, now, look,
we've all been put out
by this whole thing, right?
So, I figure we owe it to ourselves
to salvage a little dignity.
Now, me and Fenster
heard about a little job.
Why don't you just calm down?
What do you care what he has to say?
I'm just talking here
and it seems to me like Mr. Hockney
wants to hear what I got to say
and I know Fenster's down.
What about you, guy?
I'm interested, sure.
There. See?
So now, I'd like to exercise my right
to free assembly.
Why don't you just shut up?
You're missing the point.
No.
I don't want to hear anything from you.
I don't care about your job.
And
I want nothing to do with any of you.
I beg your pardon,
but you can all go to hell.
Dean Keaton gone the high road.
What is the world coming to?
Fuck him.
And that was how it started.
The five of us being brought in
on a trumped-up charge
to be leaned on by half-wits.
Okay, now, I really can't
talk about it much here.
What the cops never figured out,
and what I know now,
was that these men would never break,
never lie down,
never bend over for anybody.
Anybody-
- Who are you?
- Agent Jack Baer, FBI.
- How many dead?
- Fifteen, so far.
They're still pulling some bodies
out of the water, though.
- Any survivors?
- Yeah, there's two.
One guy's in County hospital,
but he's in a coma.
The DA has a second guy,
a cripple from New York, I think.
Listen, the chief wants this place
sealed off.
If you have any questions, give him a call.
This is Dave Kujan.
I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
If you need to reach me, contact Jeff Rabin
of the San Pedro Police Department
at extension 112.
Have a nice day.
- Why can't I see him?
- Dave, I told you,
the DA came down here last night
ready to arraign,
even before they moved him
to County, okay?
Kint's lawyer shows up five minutes later,
the DA comes out of the office looking
like the bogeyman smacked him around.
All right? They take a statement
and they cut him a deal.
- Did they charge him with anything?
- Yeah, weapons. Misdemeanor 2.
What is that?
Listen, I give the DA credit
for getting that much, you understand?
Excuse me, sir.
This whole thing has turned political.
The mayor was here last night, the chief.
This morning, the governor called, okay?
I'm telling you, this guy is protected
from up on high
by the Prince of Darkness.
- Take my word for it.
- Well, when does he post bail?
- Maybe two hours, tops.
- I want to see him.
- No, Dave.
- Well, I gotta see him, Jeffrey.
- Dave, no! I cannot...
- Listen, you gotta do this for me.
I came a long way for this.
Dave, please.
Even if I let you talk to him,
he won't talk to you.
He's paranoid about being recorded.
He knows the interrogation rooms
are all wired.
I quit.
This won't be an interrogation,
just a friendly chat to kill some time.
He will not go into the interrogation room.
- Then someplace else, then.
- Where?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
If this was a dope deal, where's the dope?
If it was a hit, who called it in?
And I'm sure you have
a host of wild theories
to answer all these questions.
They know damn well what I think.
That's crazy, and, besides,
it doesn't even matter.
The guy's got total immunity.
His story checks out.
He doesn't know what you want to know.
I don't think he does, not exactly.
But there's a lot more to his story,
believe me.
Jeffrey, look, I wanna know why
27 men died on that pier
for what looks to be $91 million
worth of dope that wasn't there.
And above all,
I want to be sure Dean Keaton's dead.
He's dead.
Come on. Two hours.
Just till he makes bail.
They're all dead.
I don't care how tough a guy
you say this Keaton was,
nobody on that boat
could've come out alive.
Is he talking?
He regained consciousness
less than an hour ago.
He spoke... not English, then he lapsed.
You think Hungarian?
I don't know.
I think that might've been what it was.
Yeah. Most of them were Hungarians.
Here, you gotta put on one of these.
Burn victims are very susceptible
to infection.
And, of course, there's no smoking.
Keep your mask up.
Please don't touch him.
Is he gonna die?
He has burns over 60% of his body,
a number of his ribs were broken...
Call hospital security, get a man
put on the door till the police get here.
- Is he dangerous?
- Yes.
Do it.
Do it, now!
Joel? Yeah, Baer. Down at LA County.
Look, the guy they pulled
out of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
Yes. Yes, I'm sure.
Well, no, no, he's all fucked up.
I can't hear you.
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
Yes.
Well, no, no. Not till I put a man on him.
Listen, send me someone
who can speak Hungarian.
Yeah, he's awake.
He's talking like a Thai hooker.
Keyser Soze.
- What?
- Keyser Soze!
Keyser Soze!
Keyser Soze.
No shit?
Joel, come in. Yeah.
Call Dan Metzheiser over at Justice,
and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan from Customs.
Nice to meet you.
He wants to ask you a few questions
before you go.
- What about?
- About a Dean Keaton, mostly.
But I'd like to start at the lineup
back in New York.
- Can I get some coffee?
- In a while. Let's talk about the lineup.
I'm really thirsty.
I used to dehydrate as a kid.
One time, I got so bad
my piss come out like snot.
I'm not kidding.
It was all thick and gooey...
I'll get your fucking coffee.
Get me one, too, while you're at it.
That guy is tense.
Tension is a killer.
I used to be in a barbershop quartet
in Skokie, Illinois.
The baritone was this guy
named Kip Diskin, big fat guy.
I mean, like, orca fat.
He was so stressed in the morning,
you know.
Verbal, you know we're trying to help you.
Sure, and I appreciate that.
And I wanna help you, Agent Kujan.
I like cops.
I would've liked to have been
a fed myself, but my CP always...
Verbal, you're not telling us everything.
I know you know something.
I told the DA
everything I know.
Verbal, I know you like Keaton.
- I know you think he's a good man.
- I know he was good.
He was a corrupt cop.
Sure, 15 years ago,
but he was a good thief.
Anyway, the cops wouldn't let him
go legit.
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
Are you trying to get a rise out of me,
Agent Kujan?
- I just wanna hear your story.
- It's all there.
May I have a cigarette?
- According to your statement...
- I need a light.
According to your statement,
you're a short-con operator,
run-of-the-mill...
According to your statement,
you're a short-con operator,
run-of-the-mill scams.
That's been suppressed.
Anything in there is inadmissible.
Oh, I know. Sweet deal you have here.
Total immunity.
Well, I do have the weapons charge.
I'm looking at
six whole months' hard time.
You know a dealer
named Ruby Deemer, Verbal?
You know a religious guy
named John Paul?
- You know Ruby's in Attica?
- He didn't have my lawyer.
I know Ruby. He's big on respect.
He's a good friend of mine,
likes me very much.
Now, I know your testimony is sealed.
Ruby's well-connected.
He's got lots of friends inside,
do a lot of favors for him.
What do you think he would say
if he found out
you dropped his name to the DA?
- There's nothing in there about Ruby.
- I'll be sure to mention that to him.
First thing on the job,
you know what I learned?
How to spot a murderer.
Let's say you arrest three guys
for the same killing.
You put them all in jail overnight.
The next morning,
whoever's sleeping is your man.
You see, if you're guilty,
you know you're caught.
You get some rest.
You let your guard down.
- You follow me?
- No.
Let me get right to the point.
I'm smarter than you
and I'm gonna find out what I wanna know
and I'm gonna get it from you,
whether you like it or not.
I'm not a rat.
Thanks.
Back when I was picking beans
in Guatemala,
we used to make fresh coffee.
Right off the trees, I mean. That was good.
This is shit,
but, hey, I'm in a police station.
Can we get started again?
Now, what happened after the lineup?
The desk sergeant
was actually trying to tell me
that he couldn't release you.
I mean, can you believe that?
You weren't even charged.
Damn police.
You know, I wanna have
pictures taken of your face.
I'll take them to the DA's office
first thing in the morning.
- Forget about it.
- Absolutely not!
I'm gonna have this thing
in front of a grand jury by Monday.
Look, I don't want
to talk about it, Edie, okay?
So, what did Fortier and Renault say?
They asked for some more time
to think about investing.
- Damn it.
- More time. It's okay.
More time for what, Edie?
No matter how you cover my tracks,
they're still gonna find out about me.
Give me some credit.
I got you this far.
Let's go to the grand jury.
You know, this isn't gonna stop
if we don't...
It's never going to stop, period.
By next week, every investor in the city
is gonna be walking away from us.
It's finished.
I'm finished.
Don't give up on me now, Dean.
It's never gonna stop.
I love you.
They ruined me in there tonight.
Do you hear me?
What?
All right.
Let's just go to my place.
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Fenster and McManus
had a cagey proposition,
a fast-jump, high-risk, long money.
We all knew it could be done.
The way I figured,
to do it wrong meant killing.
To do it right took five men.
Five men meant Keaton.
Keaton took convincing.
New York's finest taxi service.
Bullshit.
They don't operate anymore.
McManus has a friend in the 14th precinct.
They're coming out for one job, Thursday.
They're picking up a guy smuggling
emeralds out of South America.
McManus already has a fence
set to take the stuff.
A fence? Who?
Some guy in California,
his name is Redfoot.
- I never heard of him.
- You have to come.
- What's it to you whether I do it or not?
- They don't know me. You do.
They won't take me unless you go.
Look at me. I need this.
You're telling me you don't need this?
Is this your place?
Look, I'm not knocking you.
You look like you got a good little scam
going with this lawyer.
Sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
You say it's the real thing? That's cool.
You Okay?
I was out of line.
But they're never gonna stop with us,
you know that.
As clean as you could ever get,
they'll never let you go now.
This way, we hit the cops where it hurts
and we get well in the meantime.
You're sure you're okay?
I'll be all right.
Look, i...
- I sometimes get...
- Forget it.
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
So...
How do they wanna do it?
McManus wants to go in shooting,
I say no.
Fenster? Hockney?
They're pretty pissed off.
They'll do anything.
Now, I got a way to do it
without killing anyone.
But like I say,
they won't let me in without you.
Three million?
Maybe more.
No killing.
Not if we do it my way.
New York's finest taxi service
was not your normal taxi service.
It was a ring of corrupt cops in the NYPD
that ran a high-profit racket,
driving smugglers and drug dealers
all over the city.
For a few hundred dollars a mile,
you got your own blue and white,
and a police escort.
They even had their own business cards.
After a while,
somebody started asking questions
and the taxi service shut down.
Ever since then,
Internal Affairs have been waiting
to catch them in the act.
And that's where we came in.
- So, how was the flight?
- Fucking great.
Will this get me to Staten Island?
You kidding me?
This'll get you to Cape Cod.
McManus came to us
with the job, Fenster got the vans,
Hockney supplied the hardware,
I came through with how to do it
so no one got killed.
But Keaton?
Keaton put on the finishing touch.
A little fuck you
from the five of us to the NYPD.
All right, watch this, watch this.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Careful, careful, careful!
Come on, asshole!
Holy shit!
- Don't move, you fucker!
- Drop it now, motherfucker!
Drop the fucking gun! Drop it!
Don't fucking move.
Don't fucking touch a fucking thing.
- What the fuck do you guys want?
- Put your fucking thing away.
We're cops, you stupid assholes!
- Watch the glass!
- Don't fucking move, motherfucker!
You want a buckshot shampoo,
chubby?
Shut up!
Oh, fuck!
Afternoon, my little pork chops.
Now give me the shit.
- Don't move!
- Give him the fucking shit!
Give him the fucking thing!
Give him the fucking shit, man!
- Give it to me.
- Hurry up! Come on!
- Now the money.
- There's no money.
Give me the money right now,
motherfucker!
There's no fucking money.
- Give him the money right now!
- Give me the fucking money!
- Do it! Give him the money!
- Give him the money!
- Hurry up!
You know the fucking...
You know who the fuck I am?
You people know who the fuck I am? Fuck!
We do now, jerk-off.
Cocksucker.
Wait a minute. What's that?
Oh, shit.
What the fuck was...
Holy shit!
Go, go, go!
Keaton made
an anonymous phone call.
The press was on the scene
before the police were.
Strausz and Rizzi
were indicted three days later.
Within a few weeks,
50 more cops went down with them.
Everybody got it right in the ass,
from the chief on down.
It was beautiful.
I owe you $2.50.
Dr. Keaton.
- There's more here than I thought.
- When's the fence coming?
Redfoot never comes to see me,
I always go to see him.
In California?
Yes, Verbal, in California.
Fenster and I...
Wait, wait, wait. Hold the fucking phone.
You and Fenster? No, no, no, no.
- You fucking kidding me?
- Okay, so, then who's gonna go?
We all go!
What's your fucking problem, man?
My fucking problem, man,
is that you and Fenster
are off honeymooning in California,
while the rest of us are sitting here
holding our dicks.
Hey! The job's over.
Cool it.
LA's a good place to lie low for a while.
You wanna dance?
Ladies.
I would like to propose a toast.
There you go.
To Mr. Verbal,
the man with the plan.
We're gonna miss the flight.
Don't do this. Send her a note, something.
I said we'll make it.
We're gonna miss the plane.
She'll understand.
That's heartwarming. Really.
I'm weepy!
Jeff, you wanna wait outside?
You guys wanted to know
what happened after the lineup,
- I'm telling you.
- Come on, Verbal.
Who do you think you're talking to?
You expect me to believe that he retired?
For a woman?
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
- He loved her.
- Sure.
And I'm supposed to believe
that hitting the taxi service
wasn't his idea either.
It was all Fenster and McManus.
Come on, Keaton was a cop for four years.
Who else would know
the taxi service better?
That job had his name
written all over on it.
But Edie had him all turned around.
Let me tell you something,
I know Dean Keaton.
I've been investigating him
for the past three years.
The guy I know
was a cold-blooded bastard.
LAD indicted him
on three counts of murder
before he was kicked off the force.
So, don't sell me the hooker
with a heart of gold.
You got him all wrong.
Do i?>
Dean Keaton was under indictment
a total of seven times
while he was on the force.
In every case, witnesses
either reversed their testimony
to the grand jury
or died before they could testify.
When they finally did nail him for fraud,
he spent five years in Sing Sing.
He killed three prisoners inside.
Of course, I can't prove this,
but I can't prove the best part either.
Dean Keaton was dead.
Did you know that?
He died in a fire two years ago
during an investigation
into the murder of a witness
who was going to testify against him.
Two people saw Dean Keaton
walk into a warehouse he owned
just before it blew up.
They said he went in
to check a leaking gas main.
It blew up
and took all of Dean Keaton with it.
Within three months of the explosion,
the two witnesses, they were dead.
One killed himself in his car.
The other fell down an open elevator shaft.
- Agent Baer?
- Let's get this show on the road.
- Yeah, wait, just wait, hold on.
This is not what we discussed.
There are too many people in this room.
Doctor, look. I promise
we'll be out of here
before he blows his porch light, okay?
- I have a noon meeting, Baer.
- Yeah. Okay, look.
- Agent Baer, five minutes.
- Everyone just calm down, all right?
I want you to ask this man
about the shootout in the harbor.
- He says they were buying...
- Dope. We know.
He doesn't know what they were buying,
but not dope.
- People.
- What?
He needs guarantees...
- What is he talking about, guarantees?
- He says his life's in danger.
He saw the Devil, looked him in the eye.
- I'm on my way.
- No, no, no. Wait a minute.
Ask him to tell him what he told me
about the Devil.
Who's the Devil?
Keyser Soze.
Keyser Soze?
Yeah, he was in the harbor,
killing many men.
He saw Keyser Soze?
- He saw his face.
- All right. All right, look, okay?
Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
- Describe him.
- Okay.
Six weeks ago,
I get an anonymous phone call
telling me I can find Keaton
eating at Mondino's with his attorney.
And there he is.
Now, because he never profited
from his alleged death,
and because we convicted someone else
of the murder we tried to pin on him,
we had to let him go.
He was dead just long enough
for the murder rap to blow over,
and then he had lunch.
I don't know about that.
Oh, I don't think you do.
But you say you saw Keaton die.
I think you're covering his ass,
and he's still out there somewhere.
I think he's behind that whole circus
at the harbor.
My bet is he's using you
because you're stupid
and you think he's your friend.
You tell me he's dead, so be it.
I wanna be sure he's dead
before I go back to New York.
He wasn't behind anything,
it was the lawyer.
What lawyer? What lawyer, Verbal?
You know, back when I was in that
barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
You don't think that I know
you held out on the DA?
What did you leave out of that testimony?
I could be on the phone to Ruby Deemer
in 10 minutes.
- The DA gave me immunity.
- Not from me.
You get no immunity from me,
you piece of shit.
Every criminal I have put in prison,
every cop that owes me a favor,
every creep and scumbag
that walks the street for a living
will know the name of Verbal Kint.
Now, you talk to me
or that precious immunity
they seem so fit to grant you
won't be worth the paper the contract
put out on your life is printed on.
There was a lawyer.
Kobayashi.
- Is he the one that killed Keaton?
- No. But I'm sure Keaton is dead.
Convince me.
And tell me every last detail.
We arrived in Los Angeles
and met McManus' fence, Redfoot.
He had a good reputation.
Seemed like a good guy.
Still, we should have known better.
How you doing?
- Good. You?
- Not bad. Can't complain.
How's it going, Fenster?
Don't need to open it, right?
You must be Keaton.
Redfoot, Dean Keaton.
- Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint.
- Verbal, the man with the plan, huh?
You guys interested in any more work?
- We're always looking for extra work.
- We're on vacation.
Oh, well, that's too bad.
I got a ton of work
and I don't have any good people.
- Not like you guys.
- What's the job?
There's this jeweler out of Texas
named Saul.
He rents a suite in some downtown hotel.
He does free appraisals for people.
Sometimes he buys,
sometimes he doesn't.
Anyway, the word is,
he carries around a lot of cash.
So I figure, I keep the merchandise,
you keep the green.
- Simple.
- What about security?
Couple of bodyguards,
nothing you couldn't handle.
- Give me time to check it out?
- I expect nothing less from you, man.
- Good to see you. We'll call you.
- Good to see you, too.
- All right.
- Enjoy LA, huh? Get yourself laid.
Hey.
A friend of mine in New York
tells me that you knew Spook Hollis.
The way I hear it,
you did time with old Spook.
Good man, wasn't he?
I used to run dope for him.
- Too bad he got shived.
- Yeah.
I shived him.
Better you hear it from me now
than from somebody else later.
I appreciate that.
Just out of curiosity,
was it business or personal?
Bit of both.
Well, like I said,
you give me a call
if you're interested, all right?
Is there a problem?
One job. That was the deal.
One job?
That's a good one, Keaton.
Keaton fought it as best he could,
but a man can't change what he is.
He can convince anyone
he's someone else, but never himself.
It took one day with McManus nagging
and we went back to work.
So anyways, I get out of my car
and the thing is wrecked.
I look in the backseat of the other car
and this woman's totally naked.
- I'm laughing so hard I can't breathe.
- Get in the car, Saul.
Freeze, motherfucker, freeze!
Stay right there!
There's a second one here somewhere.
Give me the case.
Give me the fucking case!
Give me the fucking case.
I'm telling you for the last time.
Give me the fucking case!
- Come on!
- Hey, hey! Don't move!
Look, just hand over the case.
Hand over the fucking case.
Come on, let's go!
- Come on!
- Bad day.
- Come on, let's go!
- Fuck it.
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Fuck.
Looks like a lot of
China to me. Shit.
Guys, come on.
What are you doing?
What's it look like I'm doing?
I'm gonna kill him.
Look, we did it your way,
now we're gonna do it my way.
- Are you gonna kill him?
- I'm gonna deal with him.
- Yeah, you better deal with him.
Shut up.
What am I supposed to do with that?
I don't know, feed it to the gimp.
Ease his pain. I don't know what that is.
What do you mean you don't know?
Shut up.
I don't know.
I got thrown this job by some lawyer.
Yeah, who?
I don't know, some limey.
He's a middleman for somebody, okay?
He doesn't say, I don't ask.
- You're fucking full of shit!
- Fuck you.
- Listen to me.
We wanna meet him, okay?
That's funny.
He called me last night,
he says he wants to meet you guys.
Okay, we'll meet him.
- I'll call you.
- Good.
- Do that. No problem.
- I don't like it, Dean.
I don't like it. Wait a minute.
One more thing, tough guy.
Any more surprises,
and I'm gonna kill you.
You're such a tough guy, McManus.
But do me a favor, all right?
- Get the fuck off my dick.
- Fuck!
Don't, don't.
Put a leash on that puppy.
You know, it's an awful shame
about Saul getting whacked.
Cops are gonna be
looking for the guys who did it.
Sooner or later
they're gonna come around asking me.
You have a sweet night, ladies.
Fuck you.
- So this lawyer...
- Kobayashi.
- Came from Redfoot.
- Right.
And why leave this out
when you talked to the DA?
Dave, someone to see you.
Jack.
I've been looking all over for you.
You still after that coke
that took a walk out of that bloodbath
- in the harbor yesterday?
- Yeah.
Well, you can stop looking.
There was no coke.
I've been in LA County talking to a guy
they pulled out of a drainpipe
in San Pedro yesterday after the shootout.
He came to this morning,
he started talking.
He's part of a Hungarian mob
there to do a deal
with a bunch of gwats from Argentina,
and he says
it was definitely not a dope deal.
- But the 91 million...
- Yeah. We know.
But our man says no way on the dope.
This Hungarian tells me the whole bunch
was pulling stumps for Turkey
the next day.
They had no time to negotiate
that kind of product
and no means to move it.
- What's the money for?
- He didn't know.
No one doing the deal knew
except for a few key people.
They were all very hush about it, he says.
- Whatever it was, it was very sensitive.
- I don't get it.
They tell me you got the cripple in there
from New York?
- Yeah.
- Did he mention Keyser Soze?
Who?
Just bear with me here.
- Who's Keyser Soze?
- Oh, fuck!
We've been going over this
for an hour and a half.
What we need to do
is find Redfoot, Keaton...
- Listen.
- ...and get the hell out of here, now.
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
Somebody with power,
somebody who was capable of tracking
us from New York to Los Angeles.
Come on, Dean,
what the hell are we doing here?
We're waiting.
- Sit down.
- Bye, now.
- No.
It's hot and I'm fucking bored.
Mr. Hockney, do stay.
Mr. Keaton.
Mr. Fenster I recognize
from his mug shots,
as well as Mr. McManus.
I can only assume that you are Mr. Kint,
the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
My employer sends his gratitude,
a most unexpected benefit.
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
I have been asked by my employer
to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
What do you want?
My employer requires
your services, gentlemen.
One job, one day's work. Very dangerous.
He does not expect all of you to live,
but those of you who do
will have $91 million to divide
between you in any way you see fit.
Who's your boss?
I work for Keyser Soze.
Who's Keyser Soze?
Judging by the sudden change
in mood, Mr. Kint,
I feel sure the rest of your associates
can tell you.
I come with an offer
directly from Mr. Soze.
- An order, actually.
- What do you mean, "an order"?
In 1981, Mr. Keaton,
you participated in the hijacking
of a truck in Buffalo, New York.
The cargo was raw steel,
steel which belonged to Mr. Soze
and which was destined for Pakistan
to be used in a nuclear reactor.
A most profitable violation
of UN Regulations.
You had no way of knowing this,
Mr. Keaton,
because the fellow shipping the steel
was working for Mr. Soze
without his knowledge.
Earlier this year,
Mr. Fenster and Mr. McManus
hijacked a two-prop cargo flight
out of Newark airport.
The plane was carrying
gold and platinum wiring
also set for Pakistan.
Two months ago,
Mr. Hockney stole a truck
carrying gun parts through Queens.
Gun parts which were set to be destroyed
by the state of New York.
They were to be lost in a way station
and rerouted to Belfast.
Again, Mr. Soze using pawns
who had no knowledge.
Which brings us to Mr. Kint.
Nine months ago, one of Mr. Soze's
less-than-intelligent couriers was taken
in a complicated confidence scam
by a cripple.
He was relieved of $62,000.
Now, it has taken us
some time to find you.
Our intention was to approach you
after your apprehension in New York.
- You set up the lineup.
- Yes.
You were not to be released
until I had come to see you.
It seems Mr. Keaton's attorney,
Ms. Finneran,
was a little too effective
in expediting his release.
Holding the rest of you
became a moot point.
- What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Mr. Soze rarely works
with the same people for very long
and they never know
who they're working for.
One cannot be betrayed
if one has no people.
So, why are you telling us?
Because you have stolen from Mr. Soze,
Mr. Fenster.
All of you.
That you did not know you stole from him
is the only reason you are still alive.
He feels you owe him.
You will repay your debt.
All right, fuck the debt, and fuck you.
How do we know you work for Soze?
I don't think that is very relevant,
Mr. Hockney.
All five of you are responsible
for the murder of Saul Berg
and his bodyguards.
Mr. Redfoot can testify
to your involvement
and we can see to it that he will.
- What's your point?
- The offer is this, gentlemen.
Mr. Soze's primary interest
is narcotics.
He has been competing, shall we say,
with a group of Argentineans
for several years, now.
Competing with Mr. Soze
has taken its toll.
These Argentineans
are negotiating the sale
of $91 million in cocaine
in three days' time.
Needless to say,
this purchase will revitalize
the diminishing strength
of their organization.
Mr. Soze would like you to stop the deal.
Now, if you choose,
you may wait until after the buy.
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
Mr. Soze would like you to get to the boat
and destroy the cocaine on board.
And then you will be free
of your obligations to Mr. Soze.
You give me one good reason
why I shouldn't kill you right now.
A gift from Mr. Soze.
Good day, gentlemen.
They got my whole life in here,
everything I've ever done since I was 18.
They fucking know everything.
Everybody I've ever worked with
or did time with.
No.
- This isn't right.
- I don't know.
Who's that guy used to
talk about Soze in New York?
- Bricks Marlin.
- Yeah, he did jobs for him, indirect stuff.
And he said he always made
five times more money on it
than the job was worth.
This guy's a pipe dream.
Kobayashi's using him
for window dressing.
I don't know. This is bad.
No, it's bullshit.
This guy could be LAPD.
It's a fucking setup.
The way I hear it,
Soze's some kind of butcher.
- A peerless, psycho, fucked-up butcher.
- There is no Keyser Soze!
Who is Keyser Soze?
He's supposed to be Turkish.
Some say his father was German.
Nobody ever believed he was real.
Nobody ever knew him or saw anybody
that ever worked directly for him,
but to hear Kobayashi tell it,
anybody could have worked for Soze.
You never knew. That was his power.
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled
was convincing the world he didn't exist.
One story the guys told me,
the story I believe,
was from his days in Turkey.
There was a gang of Hungarians
that wanted their own mob.
They realized that to be in power,
you didn't need guns
or money or even numbers.
You just needed the will
to do what the other guy wouldn't.
After a while, they come into power
and then they come after Soze.
He was small-time then.
Just running dope, they say.
They come to his home
in the afternoon looking for his business.
They find his wife and kids in the house
and decide to wait for Soze.
He comes home to find
his wife raped and children screaming.
The Hungarians knew Soze was tough,
not to be trifled with,
so they let him know they meant business.
No!
They tell him they want his territory,
all his business.
Soze looks over the faces of his family,
then he showed these men of will
what will really was.
He tells him he would
rather see his family dead
than live another day after this.
He lets the last Hungarian go,
waits until his wife and kids
are in the ground
and then he goes after the rest of the mob.
He kills their kids, he kills their wives,
he kills their parents
and their parents' friends.
He burns down the houses they live in
and the stores they work in.
He kills people that owe them money.
And like that,
he's gone, underground.
Nobody's ever seen him since.
He becomes a myth.
A spook story
that criminals tell their kids at night.
"Rat on your pop,
and Keyser Soze will get you."
And no one ever really believes.
Do you believe in him, Verbal?
Keaton always said,
"I don't believe in God,
but I'm afraid of him."
Well, I believe in God,
and the only thing that scares me
is Keyser Soze.
You give any weight to this?
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser
from Justice.
He's got a file on Soze in DC.
Been a hobby of his for a couple of years.
A lot of  guys equate him to that reporter
on The Incredible Hulk.
- You've heard of him?
- What, on the street?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, a few times.
You know, outside stuff.
Somebody working for a guy
who worked for a guy
who got some money from Keyser Soze.
You know, shit like that.
You know, it could be an old badge.
You know, a hex sign.
Keep people from fucking with you
back when a name
used to mean something.
- But you're here.
- Well, shit, yeah.
I got a guy trying to
walk out of a hospital
on a fried drumstick
because he's afraid of Soze.
Yeah, I'll run it up the flagpole.
I came clean.
I told it like it happened on the boat.
So what if I left out how I got there?
It's so full of holes, the DA would've
told me to blow amnesty out my ass.
So you got what you wanted out of me,
so big fucking deal.
- So that's why you never told the DA?
- Well, you tell me, Agent Kujan.
If I told you the Loch Ness monster
hired me to hit the harbor,
- what would you say?
- Turn State's evidence.
We'll put you on the stand,
we'll hear it out.
I've got immunity now.
What can you possibly offer me?
If there really is a Keyser Soze,
he's gonna come looking for you.
Where's your head, Agent Kujan?
Where do you think
the pressure's coming from?
Keyser Soze,
or whatever you wanna call him,
he knows where I am right now.
He's got the front burner
under your ass to let me go
so he can scoop me up ten minutes later.
Immunity was just a deal
with you assholes.
I got a whole new problem
when I post bail.
So why play into his hands?
We can protect you.
Oh, gee. Thanks, Dave.
Bang-up job so far. Extortion, coercion.
You'll pardon me
if I ask you to kiss my pucker.
The same fuckers that rounded us up
and sank us into this mess
are now bailing me out? Fuck you.
You think you can catch Keyser Soze?
You think a guy like that
comes this close to getting caught
and sticks his head out?
If he comes up for anything,
it'll be to get rid of me.
After that,
my guess is
you'll never hear from him again.
What happened next?
We woke up the next morning
and Fenster was gone.
He couldn't handle the idea
of slumming for Soze.
He left us a note wishing us good luck
and took a chunk of the money
we'd scraped together.
Then what?
Well, McManus was furious.
He was talking about tracking him down
and ripping his heart out.
All sorts of shit.
That night, we got the call.
What call?
Kobayashi told us
where we could find Fenster.
All right,
let's get the fuck outta here.
We gotta bury him.
With what?
With our hands.
Oh, this is nuts.
It's dry fucking sand, McManus.
When he rots, the surfers
are gonna smell him a mile away.
- Dig, you fuck.
- Keaton, what are we gonna do?
This fucking guy is gonna kill us.
I don't know about you, peg-leg,
but I can run.
I got no problem with that.
Kobayashi doesn't seem
to have a problem with it either.
You run, and we're gonna be
digging a hole for you.
You got that?
This ain't my boy we're burying.
I don't owe anybody!
- So fuck you.
- He was my partner for five years.
We did more jobs and I saw more money
than you can ever count. So fuck you!
- 'Cause now it's payback!
- It's not payback!
It's precaution.
You want payback? You wanna run?
I don't care.
I'm not doing this for Fenster.
I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing this for me.
I'm gonna finish this thing.
This Kobayashi bastard
is not gonna stand on me.
And after they killed Fenster,
nobody would run?
I wanted to.
I thought we could make it.
Why didn't you say anything?
Believe me, I tried,
but Keaton wouldn't have it.
It was too far-fetched for him.
Keaton was a grounded guy, an ex-cop.
To a cop, the explanation
is never that complicated.
It's always simple.
There's no mystery to the street,
no arch-criminal behind it all.
If you got a dead body
and you think his brother did it,
you're gonna find out you're right.
Nobody argued with Keaton.
They just set their minds
to whacking Kobayashi.
They're coming up.
Did you hear me?
He's coming up.
He's on his way down.
Don't move.
Press 20. Do it now.
Move.
- The answer is no.
- Mr. Soze will be most upset.
Listen, you cocksucker,
there is no Keyser Soze.
You mention his name again,
and I'll kill you right now.
A strange threat, Mr. Keaton.
I can only assume that
you've come here to kill me anyway.
We know that you can get to us,
but now you know that we can get to you.
I'm giving you one last chance
to call this off.
Mr. So...
My employer has made up his mind.
- He does not change it.
- Neither do we.
You got Fenster,
but you won't be able to get all of us,
not before one of us gets through to you.
I believe you, Mr. McManus.
I most sincerely do.
You would not have been chosen,
were you not so suitable.
But I cannot make this decision.
Whatever you threaten me with is
ludicrous in comparison
to what will be done to me
if I do not carry out my orders in full.
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
I just wanted you to know that.
I'm so sorry, Mr. McManus.
I implore you, Mr. Keaton, believe me,
Mr. Soze is very real and very determined.
We'll see.
Before you do me in, Mr. McManus,
you will let me finish my business
with Ms. Finneran first, won't you?
Fuck.
What did you say?
Edie Finneran.
She's upstairs in my office
for an extradition deposition.
I requested she be put
on the case personally.
She flew in yesterday.
No matter.
Kill away, Mr. McManus.
You're lying.
Am I?
Ms. Finneran's escort
while she's here in Los Angeles.
Never leaves her side for a moment.
I thought you would be glad to know
she's in good hands.
Now, get some rest.
The boat will be ready for you on Friday.
If I see you
or any of your friends before then,
Ms. Finneran will find herself the victim
of a most gruesome violation
before she dies.
As indeed will your father, Mr. Hockney,
and your Uncle Randall in Arizona,
Mr. Kint.
I might only castrate
Mr. McManus' nephew, David.
Do I make myself clear?
We will take care
of the two bodies downstairs.
We'll add them to the cost of Mr. Fenster.
Now, if you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
It's a logistical nightmare.
Close quarters, 10, maybe 20 men.
There's no telling how many more
are gonna be below deck.
- Can we stealth these guys?
- Nah.
With all that coke, they're gonna be ready.
Which brings me
to sunny point number two.
Even if one of us gets through
and jacks the boat, we still get nothing.
What if we wait for the money?
Ten more men, at least.
Look, in my opinion, it can't be done.
Anybody who goes in there
is not coming out alive.
- I'm gonna wait for the money.
- Me, too.
- Did you hear what he just said?
- If I'm going in, I want a cut.
Me, too.
There's nothing that can't be done.
I just can't believe
we're gonna walk into certain death.
The news said it's raining in New York.
What language is that?
I don't know. Russian, I think.
Hungarian.
The package has arrived, gentlemen.
You kids ready?
I would be if I didn't have to stop
and answer you.
I'm ready.
McManus, you better be set up
in 10 seconds.
I'm ready.
I want you to stay here.
- I'm supposed to cover...
- Listen, if we don't get out of this,
I want you to take the money and go.
- Keaton, I can't...
- Find Edie.
Tell her what happened.
Tell her everything.
She knows people. She knows what to do.
If I don't get Kobayashi my way,
she'll get him her way.
- What if I...
- Please, just do what I say.
Please.
Tell her that...
Tell her I tried.
McManus, he's on his way.
I'm there.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven.
Oswald was a fag.
Hi.
How you doing?
Is there... ls there a problem?
Now.
Elvis has left the building.
Hello.
Why didn't you run?
I froze up.
I thought about Fenster
and how he looked when we buried him.
And then I thought about Keaton,
it looked like he might pull it off.
A boy came across a body
on the beach this morning.
Thrown clear when the boat burned.
Shot twice in the head.
Two guys from
the Bureau just identified him.
- What else?
- His name was Arturro Marquez,
a petty smuggler from Argentina.
He was arrested last year in New York
for trafficking.
He escapes to California.
They pick him up in Long Beach.
They're setting up extradition,
he escapes again.
Now, get this.
Edie Finneran's brought in
to advise on the proceedings.
Kobayashi.
New York faxed me a copy
of his testimony.
- He was a rat.
- Yeah, a big fucking rat.
Arturro was very opposed
to returning to prison.
So much so that he named
close to 50 people.
Guess who he named in the finale.
Keyser Soze.
There's more.
I'll tell you what I know.
Stop me when this sounds familiar.
There was no dope on that boat.
You, stay quiet.
He's here.
I know he's here. That's him.
I'm telling you, that's him.
I know he's here!
- You can't understand. That's him.
- Shut up.
That's him, you hear me?
I'm telling you, it's Keyser Soze!
- Where's Hockney?
- I don't know.
There's no coke.
- What?
- You heard me, you dumb fuck.
There's no coke!
What the fuck do you mean,
there's no coke?
I've been up and down this ship.
I've been in every fucking room!
- There's gotta be coke!
- There is nothing!
Nothing!
Don't you fuck with me.
There is no fucking coke!
I'm outta here.
I told them nothing.
I swear.
I told them nothing. Please.
McManus, what the fuck is going on?
Strangest thing.
That's what you say
in your statement.
You saw a man in a suit with a slim build.
- Wait a minute.
- I don't have a minute.
Now, are you saying
you saw Keyser Soze?
You told the DA
you didn't know who it was.
I know there was dope on that boat.
- Stop stalling, Verbal.
- I'm not stalling.
- You know what I'm getting at.
- Get out of my face.
- I got immunity.
- I don't have to take that shit.
- You know what, you know what...
You know what I'm getting at, Verbal.
Yes, you do!
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- The truth!
Try to tell me
you saw someone kill Keaton.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I did. I did.
- You're lying to me.
- I am not...
You've known,
you've known this whole fucking time.
- I don't know what you're saying.
- You know.
I did see Keaton get shot, I swear to you.
Then why didn't you help him?
You had a gun.
Why didn't you help him?
He was your friend.
Because I was afraid.
Okay?
- Afraid.
- Afraid of what?
- Afraid of...
- I knew it was Keyser Soze.
- But Keaton.
- It was Keyser Soze, Agent Kujan.
I mean, the Devil himself.
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
What if you miss?
All right. Let's get back to the pier.
- Arturro Marquez. Ever hear of him?
- What? No.
He was a stool pigeon
for the Justice Department.
He swore out a statement
to Federal marshals
saying that he had seen
and could positively identify one
Keyser Soze.
It says right here in the report.
He had intimate knowledge
of his businesses,
including, but not exclusive to,
drug trafficking and murder.
I never heard of him.
His own people were selling him
to a gang of Hungarians.
Most likely the same Hungarians that
Soze all but wiped out back in Turkey.
The money wasn't there for dope.
The Hungarians were going
to buy the one guy
that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
- I said I never heard of him.
- But Keaton did.
Edie Finneran was Marquez's
extradition advisor.
She knew who he was and what he knew.
- I don't...
- There were no drugs on that boat.
It was a hit.
A suicide mission
to whack out the one guy
that could finger Keyser Soze.
So, Soze put some thieves to it,
men he knew he could march
into certain death.
You're saying Soze
sent us to kill someone?
I'm saying Keaton did.
Verbal, he left you behind for a reason.
Just do what I tell you.
If you all knew that Soze
could find you anywhere,
why did he give you the money to run?
- He could have used you on the boat.
- He wanted me to live.
A one-time dirty cop
without a loyalty in the world
finds it in his heart
to save a worthless rat cripple?
No, sir. Why?
Edie.
I don't buy that reform story
for a minute.
Even if I did,
I certainly don't believe
he would send you to protect her.
So, Why?
Because he was my friend.
No, Verbal, he wasn't your friend.
Keaton didn't have friends.
What are you doing here?
He saved you
because he wanted it that way.
It was his will.
- Keaton was Keyser Soze.
- No.
The kind of man
who could wrangle the wills of men
like Hockney and McManus.
The kind of man
who could engineer a police lineup
through all his years of contacts in NYPD.
The kind of man
who could've killed Edie Finneran.
She was found yesterday
at a hotel in Pennsylvania,
shot twice in the head.
What do you think
about Keaton now, Verbal?
Edie?
He used all of you to get him on that boat.
He couldn't get on alone.
He had to pull the trigger himself
to make sure he got his man,
the one man that could identify him.
This is all bullshit.
You said you saw him die.
Or did you?
You had to hide
when you first heard the police cars.
You said you heard the shot
before the fire,
but you didn't see him die.
- I knew him. He would never...
- He programmed you.
He programmed you to tell us
just what he wanted you to.
He knew we were close,
you said it yourself.
Where was the political pressure
coming from?
Why were you being protected?
It was Keaton.
- Immunity was your reward.
- But why me?
Why not Fenster or McManus or Hockney?
Why me? I'm stupid, I'm a cripple.
Why me?
Because you're a cripple, Verbal.
Because you're stupid.
Because you're weaker than them.
If he's dead,
if what you say is true,
then it won't matter.
It was his idea to hit the taxi service
in New York, wasn't it?
- Come on, tell me the truth.
- It was all Keaton.
We followed him from the beginning.
I didn't know.
I saw him die.
I believe he's dead. Oh, Christ.
You're not safe on your own.
You think he's...
Keyser Soze?
I don't know, Verbal.
Keyser Soze's a shield,
or like you said, a spook story.
But I know Keaton, and someone
is out there pulling strings for you.
- Stay here and let us protect you.
- No way, I'm not bait. I post today.
You posted 20 minutes ago.
Captain Leo wants you out of here ASAP,
- unless you turn State's.
- I'll take my chances, thank you.
If someone wants to get you,
they're gonna get you out there.
Turn State's evidence.
You might never see trial.
Maybe so.
But I'm not a rat, Agent Kujan.
Fucking cops.
Excuse me, can I use your fax machine?
You'll have to sign for these, Mr. Kint.
One watch, gold.
One cigarette lighter, gold.
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
We've still got nothing, Dave.
I know what I wanted to know
about Keaton.
Which is nothing.
No matter.
He'll have to know how close we came.
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze,
if Keaton is alive,
he's not coming up again.
I'll find him.
Waste of time.
A rumor's not a rumor that doesn't die.
What?
Nothing.
Man, you're a slob.
Yeah, but it all has a system, Dave.
It all makes sense
when you look at it right.
You gotta like stand back from it,
you know?
You wanna see a real horror show?
See my garage.
Convince me and tell me
every last detail.
You know, back when I was in that
barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
Where's your head, Agent Kujan?
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
I'm sure you've heard
many tall tales.
- Bricks Marlin.
- This isn't right.
I just wanna hear your story.
Tell me every last detail.
It's all there.
And I'm telling it straight, I swear.
Some guy in California,
his name is Redfoot.
- A gift from Mr. Soze.
- Talk to me, Verbal.
- What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Using pawns...
A big fat guy.
I mean, like, orca fat.
- There was a lawyer.
- Myths, legends.
Kobayashi.
Back when I was picking beans
in Guatemala,
we used to make fresh coffee.
I know you thought
he was a good man.
I know he was good.
You tell me every last detail.
The strangest thing.
How do you shoot the Devil
in the back?
...Is protected from up on high
by the Prince of...
Tell me every last detail.
What about it, pretzel man?
What's your story?
- There was a lawyer.
- What lawyer, Verbal?
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
- Kobayashi. Kobayashi.
- Tell me every last detail.
- I work for Keyser Soze.
- Convince me. Convince me.
Every creep and scumbag
that works the street for a living
will know the name of Verbal Kint.
The cripple, did you see him?
- The cripple! Which way did he go?
- Oh. He went out that way.
I know you know something.
I know you're not telling.
I'm smarter than you
and I'm gonna find out
what I wanna know
whether you like it or not.
To a cop, the explanation is never
that complicated. It's always simple.
You know what I'm getting at,
Verbal. The truth!
There's no mystery to the street,
no arch-criminal behind it all.
Somebody with power, somebody
who's capable of tracking us...
Keyser Soze!
- It's Keyser Soze.
You think a guy like that
comes this close to getting caught
and sticks his head out?
Keyser...
Because you're stupid, Verbal.
Because you're a cripple.
What I wanna know is,
who's the gimp?
You've known,
you've known the whole fucking time.
How do I know that?
If he comes up for anything,
it'll be to get rid of me.
I'm sure Keaton is dead.
I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
First thing I learned on the job,
you know what it was?
How to spot a murderer.
They tell me you got the cripple
in there from New York
- Yeah.
- Did he mention Keyser Soze?
Who?
After that,
my guess is
you'll never hear from him again.
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled
was convincing the world he didn't exist.
And like that,
he's gone.