How you doing, Keaton?
I can't feel my legs...
...Keyser.
Ready?
What time is it?
12:30.
It all started back in New York
six weeks ago.
A truck loaded with gun parts
got jacked outside of Queens.
The driver saw nobody,
but someone fucked up.
He heard a voice.
Sometimes that's all you need.
Mr. McManus?
Christ! Don't you fucking guys
ever sleep?
- We have a warrant for your arrest.
- Fuck you, pig.
Todd Hockney?
- Who wants to know?
- New York Police Department.
Shit!
- Freeze!
- Hold it!
You sure you brought enough guys?
It's quite simple.
A restaurant that changes with the
taste without losing the esthetic.
In other words, the atmosphere
will not be painted on the walls.
Let me give you an example.
This I had to see for myself.
David.
- I'm in a meeting.
- Time for another one.
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
Special Agent Kujan, U.S. Customs.
These men are from
the New York Police Department.
You look good, Keaton.
Better than I'd have thought.
You have a problem?
A small matter of a stolen truck
loaded with guns.
Mr. Keaton?
Will you excuse us for a moment?
We have some questions to ask you
downtown. You'll be a while.
No, no, no, please.
Please, sit down.
This is a small problem.
Enjoy the meal.
Talk to you later.
It didn't make sense
that I'd be there.
These guys were hard-core hijackers.
But there I was.
At that point, I wasn't scared.
I knew I hadn't done anything
they could do me for.
Besides, it was fun.
I got to make like I was notorious.
You all know the drill.
When your number is called,
repeat the phrase you've been given.
Number one, step forward.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
Number two, step forward.
Give me the fucking keys,
you cocksucker, motherfucker...
Knock it off. Get back.
Number three, step forward.
- Hand me the keys, you cocksucker.
- In English, please.
Excuse me?
In English.
Hand me the keys, you cocksucker.
What the fuck?
Number four, step forward.
It was bullshit.
The whole rap was a setup.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
It was the cops' fault.
You don't put guys like that
into a room together.
Who knows what can happen.
Hand me the keys,
you fucking cocksucker.
This has really gotta be
embarrassing for you guys.
Someone was pissed about that
hijacked truck. The cops had nothing.
They hoped somebody would slip
and give them something.
They knew we wouldn't fight it
because they knew how to lean on us.
Our rights went out the window.
It was a violation. Disgraceful.
They went after McManus first.
Topnotch entry man.
What truck?
- The truck with the guns, fucko.
- Fucko?
He was a good guy. Crazy though.
Wanna know what Fenster told us?
- Said who?
- McManus. He told us another story.
Was that the one about
the hooker with the dysentery?
Fenster worked with McManus.
He was a tight-ass.
But when it came to the job,
he was right on. A smart man.
What are you saying?
- I said he'll flip you.
- He'll what?
- Flip you for real.
- I'm shaking.
Come on. Answer my question.
Can you hear me in the back?
I want my lawyer.
I'm gonna have your fucking badge,
cocksucker.
Todd Hockney. Good with explosives.
Without a doubt, the guy who
didn't give a fuck about anybody.
You guys don't have a leg to stand on.
I can put you in Queens
on the night of the hijacking.
Really?
I live in Queens. Did you put that
together yourself, Einstein?
You got a team of monkeys
working on this?
You know what happens if you do
another turn in the joint?
Fuck your father
and then have a snack.
- You gonna charge me?
- I'll charge you when I'm ready.
- With what?
- You know damn well, dead man.
But Keaton? He was the real prize
for them, for obvious reasons.
It was your mistake. Not mine.
Did you ever stop to ask me?
I mean, I been walking around
with the same face, the same name.
I'm a businessman.
What's that?
The restaurant business?
From now on, you're in the
getting-fucked-by-us business.
I'm gonna make you famous, cocksucker.
Like I said...
...it was your mistake. Not mine.
Now, you charge me with this shit...
...and I'll beat it.
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
Somebody's gotta do something.
I get hauled in every five minutes.
So I did a little time.
Does that mean I get railed...
...every time a truck finds its way
off the planet? Fuck them.
Fenster, will you relax? These guys
don't have any probable cause.
You're fucking-A right. No P.C.
You're goddamn right.
You do some time, never let you go.
They treat me like a criminal,
I'll end up a criminal.
You are a criminal.
Now, why you gotta go and do that?
I'm trying to make a point.
Why don't you make your point?
You're making me tired all over.
Fuck it, then.
- I heard you were dead.
- Oh, yeah?
- You heard right.
- Word I got is you hung up your spurs.
- What's that all about?
- What's this?
Rumor is Keaton's gone straight.
- I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran.
- Who's that?
A heavyweight criminal lawyer.
I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
How about it, Keaton?
You a lawyer's wife?
What retainer you giving her?
Hey, Fenster, do your friend a favor.
Tell him to keep quiet.
Dean Keaton.
Gone clean, huh?
Say it ain't so.
Or did you hit that truck?
Mac, Mac. Forget him.
Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
This whole thing was a shakedown.
- Why do you say that?
- How many times you been in a lineup?
It's always you and four dummies.
P.D. pays homeless guys
10 bucks a head half the time.
There's no way they'd line
five felons in the same row.
A voice lineup? A public defender
could get you out of that.
So why was I strip-searched?
It was the feds.
A truckload of guns get snagged.
Customs comes down on NYPD
for answers. They come up with us.
- They're clutching at straws.
- A guy's finger was up my ass.
Is it Friday already?
Yeah, lover-boy.
You want a piece?
Jump in. I'll love you.
So who are the goddamn pigs
who stole our fucking truck?
- What did you say?
- Who stole the fucking truck?
- I don't want to know.
- Who asked you, working man?
Fuck who did it.
I wanna know, who's the gimp?
- He's okay.
- Says you. What about it, pretzel man?
His name is Verbal.
Verbal Kint.
Roger, really.
People say I talk too much.
I was gonna tell you to shut up.
We met before once or twice.
In county. I was in for fraud.
You were in a lineup. What happened?
I walked. 90 days suspended.
So you did it.
All right, now look.
We've all been put out
by this whole thing, right?
So I figure we owe it to ourselves
to salvage a little dignity.
Now, me and Fenster heard
about a little job.
Why don't you just calm down?
What do you care what he says?
I'm just talking here.
It seems to me like Mr. Hockney wants
to hear it, and I know Fenster's down.
What about you, guy?
I'm interested. Sure.
There. See?
Now I'd like to exercise
my right to free assembly.
Why don't you just shut up?
You're missing the point.
No. You're missing the point.
I don't wanna hear anything from you.
I don't care about your job.
I want nothing to do with any of you.
I beg your pardon,
but you can all go to hell.
Dean Keaton...
...gone the high road.
What is the world coming to?
Fuck him.
And that was how it started.
Us five being brought in on trumped-up
charges to be leaned on by half-wits.
I really can't
talk about it much here.
What the cops never figured out,
and what I know now...
...was that these men would
never break. Never lie down.
Never bend over for anybody.
Anybody.
Who are you?
Agent Jack Baer, FBI. How many dead?
Fifteen. They're still pulling
bodies out of the water.
- Any survivors?
- There's two.
One guy's in County Hospital
in a coma.
The D.A. has the second guy,
a cripple from New York.
The chief wants this place sealed off.
If you have any questions,
give him a call.
This is Dave Kujan.
I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
If you need me, contact Jeff Rabin...
...of the San Pedro Police Department
at extension 112. Have a nice day.
- Why can't I see him?
- I told you.
The D.A. was here ready to arraign
even before they moved him to county.
Kint's lawyer shows up
five minutes later...
...the D.A. comes out looking like
the bogeyman smacked him.
They take his statement,
and they cut him a deal.
- Did they charge him with anything?
- Weapons.
Misdemeanor two.
What is that?
I give the D.A. credit for getting
that much. You understand?
Excuse me, sir.
This thing has turned political.
The mayor was here last night,
the chief.
This morning, the governor called.
This guy is protected
from up on high...
...by the Prince of Darkness.
Take my word for it.
- When does he post bail?
- Two hours, tops.
- I wanna see him.
- No, David.
I gotta see him, Jeffrey.
You gotta do this for me.
I came a long way for this.
Dave, please.
Even if I let you talk to him,
he won't talk.
He's paranoid about being recorded.
He knows interrogation rooms are wired.
This won't be an interrogation.
Just a friendly chat.
He won't go to
the interrogation room.
- Then someplace else, then.
- Where?
If this was a dope deal, where is it?
If it was a hit, who called it in?
I'm sure you have wild theories
to answer all these questions.
- You know what I think.
- That's crazy.
He's got total immunity.
His story checks out.
- He doesn't know what you wanna know.
- I don't think he does. Not exactly.
There's a lot more to his story,
believe me.
I wanna know why 27 men died
on that pier...
...for what looks to be $91 million
worth of dope that wasn't there.
And above all, I wanna be sure
Dean Keaton's dead.
He's dead.
Come on. Two hours.
Just till he makes bail.
They're all dead. I don't care
how tough a guy Keaton was.
Nobody on that boat could've
come out alive.
- Is he talking?
- He regained consciousness and spoke.
- Not English. Then he lapsed.
- Hungarian?
- I think so.
- Most of them were Hungarians.
- Put on one of these.
- Burn victims are subject to infection.
And of course, there's no smoking.
Keep your mask up.
Don't touch him.
Is he gonna die?
He has burns over 60% of his body.
Get a man on the door
till police get here.
Is he dangerous?
Yes. Do it. Do it now.
Joel? Yeah. Baer.
Down at L.A. County.
Look, the guy they pulled out
of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
No, he's all fucked up.
I can't hear you.
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
Send me a Hungarian.
He's talking like a Thai hooker.
Keyser Soze!
No shit.
Joel, call Dan Metzheiser
over at Justice...
...and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan
from Customs.
Nice to meet you.
- He wants to ask you a few questions.
- What about?
About Dean Keaton, mostly.
But I'd like to start at the lineup.
- Can I get some coffee?
- Let's talk about the lineup.
I'm really thirsty.
I used to dehydrate as a kid.
One time I got so bad
my piss come out like snot.
I'll get your coffee.
Get me one too while you're at it.
That guy is tense.
Tension is a killer.
I used to be in a quartet
in Skokie, Illinois.
The baritone was Kip Diskin.
Big, fat guy. I mean, orca fat.
He was so stressed...
You know we're trying to help you.
Sure. And I appreciate that.
And I wanna help you, Agent Kujan.
I like cops.
I would've liked to have been
a fed but...
You're not telling us everything.
I know you know something.
I told the D.A. everything I know.
Verbal, I know you like Keaton.
I know you think he's a good man.
- I know he was good.
- He was a corrupt cop.
Sure, 15 years ago.
But he was a good thief.
The cops wouldn't let him go legit.
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
Are you trying to get a rise
out of me, Agent Kujan?
I just wanna hear your story.
It's all there.
May I have a cigarette?
- According to...
- I need a light.
According to your statement,
you're a short-con operator.
Run-of-the-mill scams.
That's been suppressed.
It's inadmissible.
I know.
Sweet deal you have.
Total immunity.
Well, I do have the weapons charge.
I'm looking at six whole months
hard time.
You know a dealer named Ruby Deemer?
You know a religious guy
named John Paul?
Ruby's in Attica.
- He didn't have my lawyer.
- I know Ruby.
He's big on respect.
He's a good friend of mine.
I know your testimony's sealed.
Ruby's got friends inside
who do a lot of favors for him.
What would he say if he found out you
dropped his name to the D.A.?
- There's nothing about Ruby.
- I'll mention that to him.
First thing on the job,
I learned to spot a murderer.
You arrest three guys for a killing.
You put them in jail overnight.
Next day, whoever's sleeping
is your man.
If you're guilty, you know you're
caught. You let your guard down.
- You following me?
- No.
Let me get to the point.
I'm smarter than you.
And I'll find out
what I wanna know.
And I'm gonna get it from you.
I'm not a rat.
Thanks.
When I picked beans in Guatemala,
we made fresh coffee.
Right off the trees, I mean.
That was good.
This is shit, but I'm at a police...
Can we get started again?
Now, what happened after the lineup?
The sergeant told me
he couldn't release you.
Can you believe that?
You weren't even charged.
Police!
I wanna take pictures of your face.
I'll take them to the D.A.'s office.
Forget about it.
I'll have this at the grand jury
by Monday.
I don't wanna talk about it, Edie.
What did Fortier and Renault say?
They asked for some more time.
They just want more time.
More time for what?
No matter how you cover me,
they'll still find out about me.
Give me some credit.
I got you this far.
Let's go to the grand jury.
This won't stop...
It's never gonna stop, period.
By next week, every investor is
gonna be walking away from us.
It's finished.
I'm finished.
Don't give up on me now, Dean.
It's never gonna stop.
I love you.
They ruined me in there tonight.
Do you hear me?
What?
Let's just go to my place.
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
Let's go.
Fenster and McManus had
a cagey proposition.
A fast jump. High risk, long money.
We all knew it could be done.
I figured to do it wrong
meant killing.
To do it right took five men.
Five men meant Keaton.
Keaton took convincing.
New York's Finest Taxi Service.
Bullshit.
They don't operate anymore.
McManus has a friend in the 14th
precinct. They're doing one job.
They're picking up a guy
smuggling emeralds.
- McManus already has a fence set.
- A fence? Who?
- Some guy in California. Redfoot.
- I never heard of him.
You have to come.
- What's it to you whether I do or not?
- They don't know me. You do.
They won't take me unless you go.
- Look at me. I need this.
- Tough.
You're telling me you don't need this?
Is this your place?
You look like you got a good
little scam going with this lawyer.
Sorry.
It's okay.
You say it's the real thing.
That's cool.
You okay?
I was out of line.
But they'll never stop with us.
You know that.
As clean as you get,
they won't let you go.
This way, we hit the cops where it
hurts, and we get well in the meantime.
You're sure you're okay?
I'll be all right.
- I sometimes get...
- Forget it.
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
How do they wanna do it?
McManus wants to go in shooting.
I say no.
Fenster? Hockney?
They're pretty pissed off.
They'll do anything.
I got a way to do it
without killing anyone...
...but they won't let me in
without you.
Three million?
Maybe more.
No killing?
Not if we do it my way.
New York's Finest Taxi Service
wasn't a normal taxi.
It was a ring of corrupt cops
that ran a high-profit racket...
...driving smugglers
around the city.
For a few hundred dollars a mile,
you got a police escort.
They even had business cards.
Somebody started asking questions,
and the Taxi Service shut down.
Internal Affairs has been waiting
to catch them in the act.
That's where we came in.
- So how was the flight?
- Fucking great.
Will this get me to Staten Island?
You kidding me? This'll get you
to Cape Cod.
McManus came to us with the job.
Fenster got the vans.
Hockney, the hardware.
I figured out how to do it
so no one died.
But Keaton, Keaton put on
the finishing touch.
A little "fuck you" from
the five of us to the NYPD.
All right, watch this. Watch this.
Careful, careful!
Come on, asshole.
Holy shit!
Don't move, you fuckers!
Drop it now, motherfucker.
Drop the fucking gun. Drop it.
What do you guys want?
I'm a fucking cop, you stupid asshole!
Watch the glass!
- You want a buckshot shampoo, chubby?
- Shut up!
Oh, fuck.
Good afternoon, my little pork chops.
Give me the shit.
Give him the shit!
Give him the fucking shit, man!
Hurry up! Come on!
- Now the money.
- There's no money.
There's no fucking money.
Give him the money.
Do it! Give him the money!
Give him the money!
Hurry up!
Motherfucker, you know who I am?
Do you people know who the fuck I am?
Fuck!
We do now, jerkoff.
Wait a minute. What's that?
What the fuck...?
Holy shit!
Keaton made an anonymous call.
The press was there
before the police.
Strausz and Rizzi were
indicted 3 days later.
Within a few weeks,
50 more cops went down with them.
Everybody got it right in the ass
from the chief on down.
It was beautiful.
I owe you $2.50.
Dr. Keaton.
- There's more than I thought.
- When's the fence coming?
Redfoot never comes to see me.
I always go to see him.
In California?
Yes, Verbal, in California.
Fenster and I...
Wait. Hold the fucking phone.
You and Fenster? No, no, no.
You kidding me?
Okay, so everyone's gonna go?
We all go.
What's your fucking problem, man?
My problem is that you and Fenster are
off in California...
...while we're sitting here
holding our dicks.
The job's over.
Cool it.
L.A.'s a good place to lay low
for a while.
You wanna dance?
Ladies.
I'd like to propose a toast.
There you go.
To Mr. Verbal...
...the man with the plan.
We'll miss the flight.
Don't do this.
Send her a note, something.
I said we'll make it.
We're gonna miss the plane.
She'll understand.
That's heartwarming.
Really.
I'm weepy.
Jeff, you wanna wait outside?
You wanted to know
what happened after the lineup.
Come on, Verbal.
Who do you think you're talking to?
Do you expect me to believe
that he retired?
For a woman?
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
- He loved her.
- Sure.
Hitting the Taxi Service
wasn't his idea?
It was Fenster and McManus.
Keaton was a cop for four years.
Who knew the Taxi Service better?
- That job was his.
- But Edie had him turned around.
Let me tell you something.
I know Dean Keaton.
I've been investigating him
for three years.
The guy I knew was
a cold-blooded bastard.
I.A. indicted him on 3 counts of murder
before he was kicked off the force.
He's not the hooker
with the heart of gold.
You got him all wrong.
Do I?
Dean Keaton was under indictment
seven times while he was on the force.
In every case, witnesses
either reversed their testimony...
...or died before they could testify.
They finally nailed him
for fraud.
He spent five years in Sing Sing.
He killed three prisoners inside.
Of course, I can't prove this.
But I can't prove
the best part either.
Dean Keaton was dead.
Did you know that?
He died in a fire two years ago...
...during a murder investigation of a
witness who would testify against him.
Two people saw Dean Keaton walk into
a warehouse just before it blew up.
They said he went in to check
a leaking gas main.
It blew up and took
all of Dean Keaton with it.
Within three months
of the explosion...
...the two witnesses, they were dead.
One killed himself in his car...
...the other fell down
an open elevator shaft.
Let's get this show on the road.
There are far too many people...
We'll be out of here
before he blows his porch light.
- I have a noon meeting.
- Five minutes.
Everyone just calm down.
I want you to ask this man
about the shootout in the harbor.
- He says they were buying...
- Dope. We know.
He doesn't know what they were buying,
but not dope. People.
What?
He needs guarantees...
- What's he talking about?
- He says his life is in danger.
He saw the devil,
looked him in the eye.
- I'm on my way.
- No, no, wait a minute.
Ask him to tell him what he told me.
About the devil.
Who's the devil?
Keyser Soze.
Keyser Soze?
He was in the harbor killing many men.
He saw Keyser Soze?
He saw his face.
All right, look. Tell him
to tell her what he looks like.
Describe him.
Six weeks ago, I get a call
saying I can find Keaton...
...eating at Mondino's
with his attorney. There he is.
Because he never profited
from his alleged death...
...and we convicted someone else
of the murder...
...we had to let him go.
He was dead long enough
for the murder rap to blow over.
And then he had lunch.
I don't know about that.
I don't think you do.
But you say you saw Keaton die.
You're covering him,
and he's still out there.
He's behind the circus
at the harbor.
He's using your stupidity.
You think he's your friend.
You tell me he's dead, so be it.
I wanna be sure he's dead.
He wasn't behind anything.
It was the lawyer.
What lawyer?
When I was in that quartet
in Skokie, Illinois...
I know you held out on the D.A.!
What did you leave out of that
testimony? I can phone Ruby Deemer.
- The D.A. gave me immunity.
- Not from me.
You get no immunity from me.
Every criminal I've put in prison
or cop who owes me...
...every creep that works the street
will know the name of Verbal Kint.
You talk to me or that immunity
they deem so fit to grant you...
...won't be worth the paper the
contract on your life is printed on.
There was a lawyer.
Kobayashi.
- Was he the one that killed Keaton?
- No.
But I'm sure Keaton is dead.
Convince me.
And tell me every last detail.
We arrived in Los Angeles and met
McManus' fence, Redfoot.
He had a good reputation.
Seemed like a good guy.
Still, we should've known better.
How you doing?
- Good. You?
- Not bad. Can't complain.
How's it going, Fenster?
No need to open it, right?
You must be Keaton.
Redfoot, Dean Keaton.
- Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint.
- Verbal, the man with a plan, huh?
Interested in any more work?
- We're always looking for work.
- We're on vacation.
Oh, well. That's too bad.
I got a ton of work
and no good people.
- Not like you guys.
- What's the job?
There's this jeweler out of Texas
named Saul.
He rents a suite
in a downtown hotel.
He does appraisals. Sometimes
he buys, sometimes he doesn't.
The word is, he carries around
a lot of cash.
So I figure I keep the merchandise,
you keep the green.
- It's simple.
- What about security?
A couple of bodyguards.
Nothing you couldn't handle.
Give me time to check it out?
I expect nothing less from you, man.
Good to see you. We'll call you.
Enjoy L.A. Get yourself laid.
A friend of mine in New York tells me
that you knew Spook Hollis.
The way I hear it,
you did time with old Spook.
Good man, wasn't he?
I used to run dope for him.
Too bad he got shivved.
I shivved him.
Better you hear it from me now,
than from somebody else later.
I appreciate that.
Just out of curiosity...
...was it business or personal?
A bit of both.
Like I said...
...give me a call
if you're interested.
Is there a problem?
One job.
That was the deal.
One job?
One job!
That's a good one, Keaton.
Keaton fought it,
but a man can't change what he is.
He can convince anyone he's
someone else, but never himself.
It took one day with McManus nagging,
and we went back to work.
I get out of my car
and it's wrecked.
I look in the back seat of the car,
and this woman is naked.
I'm laughing so hard!
Get in the car, Saul.
Freeze, motherfucker!
Right there!
Here we go.
Give me the case.
Give me the fucking case!
Give me the fucking case.
I'm telling you for the last time,
give me the fucking case!
Come on! Hey, don't move.
Just hand over the case.
Hand over the fucking case.
Come on, let's go!
- Come on!
- Bad day. Fuck it.
Let's go, let's go!
Fuck!
Looks like a lot of China to me.
Shit.
Guys, come on.
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna kill him.
We're gonna do it my way.
- You gonna kill him?
- I'll deal with him.
- You better deal with him.
- I'll deal with him. Shut up.
What do I do with that?
I don't know. Feed it to the gimp.
Ease his pain.
- You don't know?
- I don't know.
- I got thrown this job by some lawyer.
- Who?
I don't know. Some limey.
He's a middleman for someone.
He doesn't say, I don't ask.
- You're fucking full of shit.
- Fuck you.
Listen to me. We wanna meet him.
That's funny.
He called me.
Says he wants to meet you guys.
- We'll meet him.
- I'll call.
- Good. Do that. No problem.
- I don't like it. Wait a minute.
One more thing...
...any more surprises,
and I'm gonna kill you.
You're such a tough guy.
Do me a favor, all right?
Get the fuck off my dick.
Better put a leash on that puppy.
You know, it's an awful shame
about Saul getting whacked.
Cops will be looking
for the guys who did it.
Sooner or later,
they'll come asking me.
You have a sweet night, ladies.
Fuck you.
So this lawyer...
Kobayashi.
...came from Redfoot.
- Right.
Why leave this out
when you talked to the D.A.?
Dave, someone to see you.
Jack.
I been looking all over for you.
You still after that coke
that took a walk from the bloodbath?
Well, you can stop looking.
There was no coke.
I been talking to a guy they pulled
out of a drainpipe after the shootout.
He came to. He started talking.
He's part of a Hungarian mob dealing
with some goats from Argentina.
- He says it wasn't a dope deal.
- But the 91 million...
Our man says no way on the dope.
He tells me the bunch was pulling
stumps for Turkey the next day.
They had no time to negotiate,
no means to move it.
- What's the money for?
- He didn't know.
No one doing the deal knew,
except a few people.
They were very hush about it,
he says.
Whatever it was,
it was very sensitive.
I don't get it.
You got the cripple in there
from New York.
- Did he mention Keyser Soze?
- Who?
Just bear with me here.
Who's Keyser Soze?
Fuck!
We've been going over this
for an hour and a half.
What we need to do is find Redfoot
and get out of here now.
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
Somebody with power...
...who was capable of tracking us
from New York to L.A.
- What the hell are we doing here?
- We're waiting.
Sit down.
No. It's hot, and I'm fucking bored.
Mr. Hockney, do stay.
Mr. Keaton.
Mr. Fenster, I recognize from
his mug shots, as well as Mr. McManus.
I can only assume
that you are Mr. Kint...
...the gentleman who disposed
of Saul Berg.
My employer sends his gratitude.
A most unexpected benefit.
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
I have been asked by my employer
to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
- What do you want?
- My employer requires your services.
One job.
One day's work. Very dangerous.
He doesn't expect all of you to live,
but those who do...
...will have $91 million to divide
between you in any way you see fit.
Who's your boss?
I work for Keyser Soze.
Who's Keyser Soze?
Judging by the sudden change in mood,
I'm sure your associates can tell you.
I come with an offer
directly from Mr. Soze.
An order, actually.
What do you mean, "an order"?
In 1981, Mr. Keaton,
you participated...
...in the hijacking of a truck
in Buffalo, New York.
The cargo was raw steel.
Steel which belonged to Mr. Soze...
...and which was destined for Pakistan
to be used in a nuclear reactor.
A most profitable violation
of UN regulations.
You had no way of knowing this.
The man shipping the steel
was working for Mr. Soze...
...without his knowledge.
Earlier this year,
Mr. Fenster and Mr. McManus...
...hijacked a two-prop cargo flight
out of Newark airport.
The plane was carrying gold and
platinum wiring, also set for Pakistan.
Two months ago...
...Mr. Hockney stole a truck
carrying gun parts through Queens.
Gun parts which were set to be
destroyed by the state of New York.
They were to be lost in a way station
and re-routed to Belfast.
Again, Mr. Soze using pawns
who had no knowledge.
Which brings us to Mr. Kint.
Nine months ago, one of Mr. Soze's
less-than-intelligent couriers...
...was taken in a complicated
confidence scam by a cripple.
He was relieved of $62,000.
Now, it has taken us some time
to find you.
Our intention was to approach you
after your apprehension in New York.
You set up the lineup.
You were not to be released
until I had come to see you.
It seems Mr. Keaton's attorney,
Miss Finneran...
...was a little too effective...
...in expediting his release. Holding
the rest was a moot point.
- What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Mr. Soze rarely works with
the same people.
They never know
who they work for.
One cannot be betrayed
if one has no people.
So why are you telling us?
Because you have stolen from Mr. Soze,
Mr. Fenster. All of you.
That you did not know you did
is the only reason you're still alive.
He feels you owe him.
You will repay your debt.
Fuck the debt and fuck you.
How do we know you work for Soze?
I don't think that is very relevant,
Mr. Hockney.
You all are responsible for the murder
of Saul Berg and his bodyguards.
Mr. Redfoot can testify to your
involvement. We can see that he will.
What's your point?
The offer is this, gentlemen.
Mr. Soze's primary interest
is narcotics.
He has been competing,
shall we say...
...with Argentineans
for years now.
Competing with Mr. Soze has
taken its toll.
These Argentineans are negotiating
the sale...
...of $91 million in cocaine
in three days' time.
Needless to say,
this purchase will revitalize...
...the diminishing strength
of their organization.
Mr. Soze would like you
to stop the deal.
If you choose, you may wait
until after the buy.
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
Mr. Soze would like you to get to the
boat and destroy the cocaine onboard.
And then you will be free
of your obligations to Mr. Soze.
You give me one good reason why
I shouldn't kill you right now.
A gift from Mr. Soze.
Good day, gentlemen.
They got my whole life in here.
Everything I've ever done.
They know everything.
Everybody I've ever worked with
or did time with.
- This isn't right.
- I don't know.
Who's that guy used to talk about Soze
in New York?
Bricks Marlin.
Yeah, he did jobs for him.
Indirect stuff.
He made five times more money
than it was worth.
This guy's a pipe dream. Kobayashi's
using him for window-dressing.
I don't know. This is bad.
No, it's bullshit. This guy
could be LAPD. It's a fucking setup.
The way I hear it,
Soze's some kind of a butcher.
A peerless, psycho, fucked-up butcher.
There is no Keyser Soze!
Who is Keyser Soze?
He's supposed to be Turkish.
Some say his father was German.
Nobody ever believed he was real.
Nobody knew him or saw anybody
that worked directly for him.
To hear Kobayashi tell it,
anybody could've worked for him.
You never knew. That was his power.
The greatest trick
the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the world
he didn't exist.
One story the guys told me,
the story I believe...
...was from his days in Turkey.
A gang of Hungarians
wanted their own mob.
They realized that to be in power...
...you didn't need guns or money
or even numbers.
You just needed the will to do
what the other guy wouldn't.
After a while, they come into power.
They went after Soze.
He was smalltime then.
Just running dope, they say.
They come to his home
in the afternoon...
...looking for his business.
They find his wife and kids
and decide to wait for Soze.
He comes home...
...to find his wife raped
and children screaming.
The Hungarians knew Soze was tough,
not to be trifled with.
So they let him know
they meant business.
They tell him they want his
territory, all his business.
Soze looks over the faces
of his family.
Then he showed these men of will
what will really was.
He tells them he would rather
see his family dead...
...than live another day after this.
He lets the last Hungarian go.
He waits until his family is
in the ground, then goes after the mob.
He kills their kids.
He kills their wives.
He kills their parents,
their parents' friends.
He burns down the houses
they live in...
...the stores they work in.
He kills people that owe them money.
And like that...
...he's gone.
Underground.
Nobody's ever seen him since.
He becomes a myth. A spook story that
criminals tell their kids at night.
"Rat on your pop,
and Keyser Soze will get you."
And no one ever really believes.
Do you believe in him, Verbal?
Keaton always said:
"I don't believe in God
but I'm afraid of him."
Well, I believe in God.
And the only thing that scares me...
...is Keyser Soze.
Do you give any weight to this?
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser.
He's got a file on Soze in D.C.
It's a hobby of his.
A lot of guys equate him to that
reporter on The Incredible Hulk.
- You've heard of him?
- Where? On the street?
Yeah, a few times. Outside stuff.
Somebody worked for a guy
who got some money...
...from Keyser Soze.
You know, shit like that.
It could be an old badge.
A hex sign...
...to keep people from fucking with you.
- But you're here.
- Well, shit, yeah.
A guy left a hospital on a fried
drumstick because he's afraid of Soze.
I'll run it up the flagpole.
I came clean. So what if I left out
how I got on the boat.
It's so full of holes, the D.A. would've
told me to blow amnesty out my ass.
Big fucking deal.
That's why you never told the D.A.?
You tell me, Agent Kujan.
If I said the Loch Ness monster
hired me, what would you say?
Turn state's evidence.
We'll put you on the stand.
I've got immunity.
What can you offer?
If there is a Soze,
he's gonna come for you.
Where's your head?
Where do you think
the pressure's coming from?
Soze knows where I am now.
He's got a burner under you to let
me go, so he can scoop me up later.
Immunity was just a deal with you.
I got a new problem when I post bail.
Why play to him?
We can protect you.
Gee, thanks, Dave.
Bang-up job so far.
Extortion. Coercion.
Pardon me, kiss my pucker.
The fuckers that rounded us up and sank
us into this mess are bailing me out?
You think you can catch Keyser Soze?
You think he'd come this close to
getting caught and stick his head out?
If he comes up,
it'll be to get rid of me.
After that...
...my guess is, you'll never
hear from him again.
What happened next?
The next morning Fenster was gone.
He couldn't handle the idea
of slumming for Soze.
He left us a note and took a chunk
of the money we'd scraped together.
Then what?
McManus was furious.
He was talking about tracking him down
and ripping his heart out.
That night we got the call.
What call?
Kobayashi told us where
we could find Fenster.
All right.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
We gotta bury him.
With what?
With our hands.
This is nuts.
It's dry fucking sand.
When he rots, the surfers
are gonna smell him a mile away.
Fuck!
What are we gonna do?
This guy's gonna kill us.
I don't know about you, but
I can run. I got no problem with that.
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have
a problem with it either.
If you run...
...we'll be digging
a hole for you. You got that?
This ain't my boy we're burying.
I don't owe anybody!
So fuck you.
He was my partner for five years.
We did more jobs and saw more money
than you can count.
So fuck you!
Because now it's payback.
It's not payback!
It's precaution.
You want payback? You wanna run?
I don't care.
I'm not doing this for Fenster.
I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing this for me.
I'm gonna finish this thing.
This Kobayashi bastard
isn't gonna stand on me.
After they killed Fenster,
nobody ran?
I wanted to.
I thought we could make it.
Why didn't you say anything?
I tried, but Keaton wouldn't have it.
It was too far-fetched for him.
Keaton was a grounded guy. An ex-cop.
To a cop, the explanation
is never that complicated.
There's no mystery to the street.
No archcriminal behind it all.
If you got a body and think
his brother did it, you're right.
Nobody argued with Keaton. They just
set their minds to Kobayashi.
They're coming up.
Did you hear me? He's coming up.
He's on his way down.
Don't move.
Press 20. Do it now.
Move!
The answer is no.
- Mr. Soze will be most...
- There is no Keyser Soze.
Mention him again,
I'll kill you.
A strange threat. I can only assume
you've come here to kill me anyway.
Now, we know that you can get to us.
But now you know that
we can get to you.
I'm giving you one last chance
to call this off.
Mr. S...
My employer has made up his mind.
He does not change it.
Neither do we.
You got Fenster, but you
won't be able to get all of us.
Not before we get to you.
I believe you, Mr. McManus.
I most sincerely do.
You wouldn't be chosen
were you not so suitable.
But I cannot make this decision.
What you threaten me with is ludicrous
compared to what will be done to me...
...if I do not carry out
my orders in full.
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
I just wanted you to know that.
I'm so sorry, Mr. McManus.
I implore you, Mr. Keaton,
believe me...
...Mr. Soze is very real
and very determined.
We'll see.
Before you do me in, Mr. McManus...
...you'll let me finish my business
with Ms. Finneran, won't you?
What did you say?
Edie Finneran.
She's upstairs. In my office.
For an extradition deposition.
I requested she be put
on the case personally.
She flew in yesterday.
No matter.
Kill away, Mr. McManus.
You're lying.
Am I?
Ms. Finneran's escort while
she's here in Los Angeles.
Never leaves her side.
I thought you'd be glad to know
she's in good hands.
Get some rest. The boat
will be ready Friday.
If I see you or any of your friends
before then...
...she'll find herself the victim of a
gruesome violation before she dies.
As indeed, will your father,
Mr. Hockney...
...and your Uncle Randall
in Arizona, Mr. Kint.
I might only castrate
Mr. McManus' nephew, David.
Do I make myself clear?
Take care of the bodies downstairs.
We'll add them to the cost
of Mr. Fenster.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
It's a logistical nightmare.
Close quarters.
Ten, maybe 20 men.
No telling how many more
will be below deck.
- Can we stealth these guys?
- No.
With all that coke,
they're gonna be ready.
Which brings me
to sunny point number two.
Even if we get through and
jack the boat, we got nothing.
What if we wait for the money?
Ten more men at least.
Look, in my opinion, it can't be done.
Whoever goes there
won't come out alive.
I'm gonna wait for the money.
- Me too.
- Did you hear what he just said?
- If I'm going in, I want a cut.
- Me too.
There's nothing that can't be done.
I can't believe we're
walking into certain death.
The news said
it's raining in New York.
What language is that?
I don't know.
Russian, I think.
Hungarian.
The package has arrived, gentlemen.
You kids ready?
I would be if I didn't
have to stop and answer you.
I'm ready. McManus, you better be
set up in 10 seconds.
I'm ready.
I want you to stay here.
I'm supposed to cover...
If we don't get out of this,
take the money and go.
Find Edie. Tell her what happened.
She knows people and knows what to do.
If I don't get Kobayashi my way,
she'll get him her way.
Just do what I say.
Please.
Tell her that...
Tell her I tried.
McManus...
...he's on his way.
I'm there.
One, two, three, four...
...five, six, seven...
Oswald was a fag.
How you doing?
Is there...
Is there a problem?
Now.
Old MacDonald had a farm
E-I-E-I-O
And on that farm he shot some guys
Bada-boom
Bada-bing-bang-boom
Elvis has left the building.
Why didn't you run?
I froze up.
I thought about Fenster,
how he looked when we buried him.
I thought about Keaton.
It looked like he might pull it off.
A boy came across a body on the beach
today. Shot twice in the head.
Two guys from the Bureau
just identified him.
Arturro Marquez.
A petty smuggler from Argentina.
Arrested last year
in New York for trafficking.
He escapes to California.
They pick him up in Long Beach.
They're setting up extradition,
he escapes again.
Now, get this.
Edie Finneran's brought in
to advise on the proceedings.
Kobayashi.
New York faxed me a copy
of his testimony. He was a rat.
A big rat.
Arturro was very opposed
to returning to prison.
So much so that he named
close to 50 people.
Guess who he named in the finale?
Keyser Soze.
There's more.
I'll tell you what I know.
Stop me when this sounds familiar.
There was no dope on that boat.
You, stay quiet.
He is here.
I know he is here.
That's him.
I'm telling you, that's him.
I know he is here!
- You can't understand. That's him.
- Shut up!
That's him! You hear me?
I'm telling you, it's Keyser Soze!
- Where's Hockney?
- I don't know.
There's no coke!
You heard me, you dumb fuck!
I've been up and down this ship!
Every fucking room!
There is nothing!
Nothing!
Don't you fuck with me!
There is no fucking coke!
I'm out of here.
I told them nothing.
I swear.
I told them nothing. Please.
McManus.
What the fuck is going on?
The strangest thing...
You say you saw a man in a suit
with a slim build.
- Wait a minute.
- No.
You saw Soze? You told the D.A.
you didn't know who it was.
I know there was dope there.
You know what I'm getting at!
Get out of my face.
I've got immunity.
I don't have to take that shit!
You know what I'm getting at.
The truth! Try to tell me
you saw someone kill Keaton.
- I did.
- You're lying to me!
You've known this whole fucking time.
I don't know what you're saying.
I saw Keaton get shot.
Then why didn't you help him?
You had a gun.
He was your friend.
Because I was afraid.
Okay?
- Afraid.
- Afraid of what?
I knew it was Keyser Soze.
It was Keyser Soze, Agent Kujan.
I mean, the devil himself.
How do you shoot the devil
in the back?
What if you miss?
All right.
Let's get back to the pier.
Ever hear of Arturro Marquez?
What? No.
He was a stool pigeon
for the Justice Department.
He swore out a statement
saying that he had seen...
...and could positively identify
one Keyser Soze.
It says right here:
"He had knowledge of his businesses,
including but not exclusive...
...to trafficking and murder."
- I never heard of him.
His own people were selling him
to Hungarians.
Most likely the Hungarians that
Soze all but wiped out in Turkey.
The money wasn't for dope.
The Hungarians were buying the one guy
that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
I never heard of him.
Keaton did. Edie Finneran
was Marquez's extradition adviser.
She knew what he knew.
- I don't...
- There were no drugs on that boat.
It was a hit. A suicide mission
to whack out the one guy...
...that could finger Keyser Soze.
Soze put some thieves to it.
Men he knew he could march
into certain death.
You're saying Soze
sent us to kill someone?
Keaton did.
He left you behind for a reason.
Just do what I tell you.
If you all knew that Soze
could find you anywhere...
...why did he give you the money
to run? He could use you on the boat.
He wanted me to live.
A one-time dirty cop without a
loyalty in the world wants to save...
...a worthless cripple?
No, sir. Why?
- Edie.
- I don't buy that reform story.
Even if I did, I don't believe
he would send you to protect her.
So why?
Because he was my friend.
No, Verbal. He wasn't your friend.
Keaton didn't have friends.
Why are you here?
He saved you because he wanted it
that way. It was his will.
Keaton was Keyser Soze!
He could wrangle the wills
of men like Hockney and McManus.
He could engineer a police
lineup through his contacts in NYPD.
He's a man who could've killed
Edie Finneran!
She was found yesterday in a hotel in
Pennsylvania, shot twice in the head.
What do you think about Keaton now?
Edie?
He used you to get on the boat.
He couldn't get on alone.
He had to pull the trigger himself
to make sure he got his man.
The one man that could identify him.
This is all bullshit.
You said you saw him die.
Or did you?
You hid when you heard the police.
You said you heard the shot
before the fire.
But you didn't see him die.
I knew him. He'd never...
He programmed you.
He programmed you to tell us what he
wanted you to. He knew we were close.
Where was the pressure coming from?
Why were you protected?
It was Keaton.
Immunity was your reward.
But why me?
Why not Fenster, McManus or Hockney?
Why me?
I'm stupid. I'm a cripple.
Because you're a cripple.
Because you're stupid.
Because you're weaker than them.
If he's dead...
...if what you say is true,
then it won't matter.
It was his idea to hit
the Taxi Service, wasn't it?
- Come on, tell me the truth.
- It was all Keaton.
We followed him from the beginning.
I didn't know.
I saw him die.
I believe he's dead. Oh, Christ!
You're not safe on your own.
You think he's...
Keyser Soze?
I don't know, Verbal.
Keyser Soze's a shield.
Or like you said, "a spook story."
But I know Keaton. And someone is
out there pulling strings for you.
- Stay here and let us protect you.
- I'm not bait. I post today.
You posted 20 minutes ago.
Capt. Leo wants you
out of here ASAP.
- Unless you turn state's.
- I'll take my chances.
If someone wants to get you,
they're gonna get you out there.
Turn state's evidence.
You might never see trial.
Maybe so.
But I'm not a rat, Agent Kujan.
Fucking cops!
Excuse me.
Can I use your fax machine?
You'll have to sign for these,
Mr. Kint.
One watch, gold.
One cigarette lighter, gold.
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
We still got nothing, Dave.
I know what I wanted
to know about Keaton.
Which is nothing.
No matter.
He'll have to know how close we came.
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze...
...if Keaton is alive,
he's not coming up again.
I'll find him.
Waste of time.
A rumor's not a rumor
that doesn't die.
What?
Nothing.
Man, you're a slob.
Yeah, but it all has a system, Dave.
It don't make sense when you look right
at it. You gotta stand back from it.
Wanna see a real horror show?
You should see my garage.
Convince me.
When I was in that quartet
in Skokie...
Where's your head?
What we need to do is think.
Think back.
I'm sure you've heard tall tales.
- This isn't right.
- I just want your story.
It's all there.
I'm telling it straight, I swear.
- guy in California
named Redfoot.
A gift from Mr. Soze.
- What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Big, fat guy.
I mean, orca fat.
- There was a lawyer.
- Kobayashi.
- never see him again.
- in Guatemala, we made
fresh coffee.
...- thought he was a good man.
- I know he was good.
And tell me every last detail.
How do you shoot the devil
in the back?
He's protected from up on high
by the Prince...
What about it, pretzel man?
- There was a lawyer.
- What lawyer?
- I am Mr. Kobayashi.
- Kobayashi. Kobayashi.
Tell me every last detail.
I work for Keyser Soze.
Convince me.
Every creep that walks the street
will know the name of Verbal Kint.
The cripple, did you see him?
Which way did he go?
He went out that way.
I know you know something.
I'm smarter than you.
And I'll find out what I wanna know.
To a cop, the explanation
is never that complicated.
There's no mystery to the street.
No archcriminal...
Somebody with power, who was capable
of tracking us from New York to L.A.
You think he'd come
this close to getting caught...
...and stick his head out?
Because you're stupid.
Because you're a cripple.
You've known the whole fucking time!
Keaton's dead.
I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
First thing I learned on the job
was how to spot a murderer.
- the cripple from New York,
he mention Keyser Soze?
Who?
And after that...
...my guess is, you'll
never hear from him again.
The greatest trick
the devil ever pulled...
...was convincing the world
he didn't exist.
And like that...
...he's gone.
.:: YIFYMOVIES.IS ::.
Watch YIFY Movies Online For Free