Name?
Horowitz, Salomon.
Schneider, Sarah.
Birnbaum, Olga.
Over there.
Kommen Sie doch. (Come, come).
Over there!
Isak Hudes.
Zucker, Helena.
Hirsch, Salomon?
Hirsch, Salomon.
Hauptman, Chaim!
Weisman! Weisman, Marcus!
Feber, Ludwig!
Feber, Ludwig.
Elsa Bauman.
-Josef Klein.
-Klein.
Davidowich, Ignacy.
Paula Biffer.
Nadel, Rachela.
-Steiner, Gertruda.
-Steiner, Hilda.
-Jerzy, you know who that man is?
-I don't know.
Let's get together, please.
Smile. Good.
Yes, sir.
Bring them over a round of drinks.
Very good, sir. And who
shall I say they are from?
You can say they are from me.
From the gentleman.
Where?
Do you know him?
Find out who he is.
Yes, sir.
Agnieszka, I would give anything
to hear you sing tonight.
But I know you won't.
You embarrass me.
What's he doing?
Stay here.
How are you doing?
You'd leave a woman alone at the
table in a place like this?
Sweetheart, you're the
picture of loneliness.
Oh.
Mmm, what a lovely fragrance.
You are breaking my heart.
An extra chair, please.
Vodka for my friend.
And for the lady?
Pernod.
Come to the table, girls!
Drink with us!
Come to us! Marry us!
Thank you.
I'll tell you what I
mean by cooperative.
Two days after the law is passed
that all Jews have to wear the star,
the Jewish tailors are turning
them out by the gross
in a variety of fabrics
at three zloty each.
Tell me about your cellar wines.
-I have an excellent German Riesling. 1937.
-Mmm, French.
-A Bordeaux. Chateau Latour, '28, '29?
-No, I'm sorry.
It's as if they have no idea
what kind of law it is.
As if it's the emblem of a riding club.
-A Margaux, '29?
-No, no, we don't have that.
-Burgundy then? A Romanee-Conti, '37?
-Yes.
It's human nature.
'We'll do this to avoid that.'
That's what they have done
since thousands of years.
It's what they do.
They weather the storm.
But this storm is different. This is
not the Romans. This storm is the SS.
Martin.
Yes, sir.
Who is that man?
That's Oskar Schindler!
An alle Juden!
(To all Jews)
Ab sofort ist es allen Juden untersagt...
(From now on all Jews are forbidden...)
Fleisch auf koschere Art zuzubereiten.
(to prepare kosher meat)
Meldung an alle Juden. Ab sofort...
(Message to all Jews. From now on...)
-Rabbi...
-Private property cannot be confiscated.
How long are the schools
going to be closed?
I do not know.
'Article 47, pillage is
formally prohibited.'
You don't know anything!
I am familiar with the Hague Convention.
Religious...
They come into our house and tell
us we don't live there anymore.
It now belongs to a certain SS officer.
Please. I only know what they tell me.
And what they tell me
changes from day to day.
Aren't you supposed to be able to help?
I mean, what if I just
took this thing off?
What are they going to do about it?
They will shoot you.
-Why don't you stop this silly talk?
-Itzhak Stern!
I'm looking for Itzhak Stern.
Are you Itzhak Stern or not?
-I am.
-Where can we talk?
There's a company you did the
books for on Lipowa Street.
Made what? Pots and pans?
By law, I have to tell
you, sir, I'm a Jew.
Well, I'm a German. So there we are.
A good company, you think?
Modestly successful.
I know nothing about enamelware.
Do you?
I was just the accountant.
Simple engineering though,
wouldn't you think?
Change the machines around,
whatever you do...
you could make other
things, couldn't you?
Field kits, mess kits.
Army contracts.
Once the war ends, forget
it, but for now it's great.
You can make a fortune,
don't you think?
I think most people right now
have other priorities.
Like what?
I'm sure you'll do just fine
once you get the contracts.
In fact, the worse things get,
the better you'll do.
Well, I can get the signatures I need.
That's the easy part.
Finding the money to buy
the company, that's hard.
You don't have any money?
Not that kind of money.
You know anybody?
Jews, yeah. Investors.
You must have contacts in the Jewish
business community, working here.
What community? Jews can
no longer own businesses.
That's why this one's in receivership.
But they wouldn't own it.
I'd own it. I'd pay them back
in product, pots and pans.
Pots and pans.
Something they can use.
Something they can feel in their hands.
They can trade it on the black market,
do whatever they want.
Everybody's happy.
If you want, you could
run the company for me.
Let me understand.
They'd put up all the
money, I'd do all the work.
What, if you don't mind
my asking, would you do?
I'd make sure it's known
the company's in business.
I'd see that it had a certain panache.
That's what I'm good at, not the work.
Not the work.
The presentation.
I'm sure I don't know anybody
who'll be interested in this.
Well, they should be, Itzhak Stern.
Tell them they should be.
Achtung! Achtung!
(Attention! Attention!)
An alle Juden. Ab sofort ist es verboten...
(To all Jews. From now on it is forbidden ...)
I've got a client who'll sell
marks for zloty at 2.45-to-1.
Wool, mink collar.
It's a nice coat.
She'll trade it for ration coupons.
Wicks, for lamps.
You have a truckload of wicks?
What am I going to do with
a truckload of wicks?
Nine by 12, nine by 14.
-I don't know.
-Big, beautiful, Persian.
Past.
What?
You don't recognize this?
It's shoe polish.
In metal containers?
You asked for shoe polish.
In metal containers. This is glass.
It's not what I asked for.
-What's the difference?
What's the difference?
My client sold it to his client,
who sold it to the German army.
Only by the time it got there, because
of the freezing cold, it broke.
All 10,000 units.
Mmm, ooh, ooh, ooh.
This is not my problem.
-This is not his problem.
-This is not your problem?
This is not my problem.
All right.
The German army wants to
find out where it came from.
I am going to make sure they find out.
Now it's your problem.
You, be quiet!
Metal containers.
Hello.
Pardon me for interfering,
but that's a nice shirt.
Nice shirt.
Do you know where I can find
a nice shirt like that?
Like this?
It's illegal to buy or sell
anything on the street.
We don't do that.
We're here to pray.
Do you have any idea how much
a shirt like this costs?
Nice things cost money.
How many?
I'm going to need some other
things, too, as things come up.
This won't be a problem.
From time to time.
Achtung! Achtung!
(Attention! Attention)
Name? Adresse?
(Name? Address?)
Formular ausfullen!
(Fill out the form!)
Weiter, weiter!
(Move on, move on!)
Nicht drangeln!
(Do not push!)
Kommen Sie hier!
(Come here!)
Stehen sie sich doch an!
(Stand by!)
Achtung, Achtung!
(Attention! Attention)
Alle Juden sind verpflichtet...
(All Jews are accommodated...)
im abgesonderten judischen Bezirk zu wohnen.
(in the separate Jewish district.)
Nichteinhaltung der Meldepflicht bei der
(Failure to comply with the obligation to report)
Einwohnerbehorde beim Militargericht.
(to the resident's authority will be dealt by the military court).
This is obviously the right place.
How are you doing?
Goodbye, Jews!
-This is the vecheka, Moyshe.
-Ojciec.
Nyne, this kan neash zyane.
(No. This can not be true.)
Oh, my God.
Oy, God. Oh, my God.
It could not be better.
It could be worse.
How? Tell me.
How on earth could it
possibly be worse?
Dzien dobry.
(Good morning!)
(Good morning).
Dzien dobry.
Good morning).
(Good morning).
Dzien dobry.
-Hey, Goldberg.
-Poldek.
What's this?
The Judenrat has its own
police now, Poldek.
You don't say.
Ordnungsdienst.
(By order)
-I'm a policeman now, could you believe it?
-It's hard to believe.
No, it's not hard to believe.
It's a good racket, Poldek.
The only racket here.
Look, maybe I could put in a good
word for you with my superiors.
Your superiors?
Come on, they are not as bad
as everyone says.
Well, they're worse than everyone says,
but it's a lot of money.
A lot of money.
Give me my housing assignment.
Come on.
You look funny in that hat, Goldberg.
You look like a clown, you know.
He's a very important man. Just
give him two minutes of your time.
-Since when did time cost money?
-Just sit down and listen.
Please. Sir?
For each 1,000 you invest,
I will repay you with...
two hundred kilos of
enamelware a month,
to begin in July and to
continue for one year.
After which time, we're even.
That's it. It's very simple.
Not good enough.
It's not good enough.
Not good enough?
Look where you're living. Look where
you've been put. 'Not good enough.'
A couple of months ago you'd be right.
Not anymore.
Money's still money.
No, it is not.
That's why we're here.
Trade goods, that's the only currency
that'll be worth
anything in the ghetto.
Things have changed, my friend.
Did I call this meeting?
You told Mr. Stern you
wanted to speak to me.
I'm here. I've made you a fair offer.
Fair would be a percentage
in the company.
Forget the whole thing. Get out.
How do we know that you
will do what you say?
Because I said I would.
You want a contract?
To be upheld by what court?
I said what I'll do.
That's our contract.
...mielismy racje.
(...we were right)
Piec, szesc, siedem,
(Five, six, seven)
osiem, dziewiec.
(eight, nine)
The standard SS rate for Jewish skilled
labourers is seven marks a day,
five for unskilled and women.
This is what you pay
the Reich Economic Office.
The Jews themselves receive nothing.
Poles you pay wages.
Generally, they get a little more.
Are you listening?
What was that about the SS?
The rate? The what?
The Jewish worker's salary.
You pay it directly to the
SS, not to the worker.
-He gets nothing.
-But it's less.
It's less than what I would pay a Pole.
It's less.
That's the point I'm trying to make.
Poles cost more.
Why should I hire Poles?
An enamelware factory
over at Lipowa Street.
It's owned by a German.
But it's outside the ghetto, so
you can barter for extra goods,
for eggs, I don't know what you need,
with the Polish workers.
You can't get it here.
Also, he's asking for
10 healthy women for the...
I am healthy.
Bring your sister, okay?
Chodz.
(Come.)
You need to convince
them you have a trade,
something valuable to the war effort.
-Like what?
-What if you don't?
I'm a musician.
Your name goes on a list.
I hear your name goes on a list
and they put you on trucks...
-No, no, that's not true.
-You're a musician?
-Lisa!
-Yeah.
I'd find a good hiding
place if I were you.
I'm not going to hide like some animal.
There are places to hide.
I'm a graduate of the
University of Lviv.
I used to work at the
hydroelectric station in Roznow.
Blauschein.
(Blue card).
I'm gonna get the necessary papers
because this card is no good anymore.
You can stay in this line all day,
you'll still get one of these.
They are no good. You'll
have to leave the line now,
then you'll get
a blue card, a Blauschein,
to say that you are
an essential worker.
I'll get these papers
for you at Pankiewicz.
Pharmacist. Just there, look.
Guess who is here?
Poldek!
Enjoying the weather, Poldek?
Enjoying the lines?
Need some shoe polish?
In a metal container maybe?
Not essential?
I think you misunderstand
the meaning of the word.
No Blauschein (Blue card), sir.
Stand over there. Move. Next!
What do you mean, 'Not essential'?
I teach history and literature.
Since when it's not essential?
He's a metal polisher.
It was not right?
It's very good. He's 53 years old.
It's too new.
Mmm. Thank you.
You're crazy. You left
it in your drawer.
How many times have I told you?
Your work certificate you keep
in your pocket at all times.
And you leave yours in your drawer.
How many times I've told you?
I'm a metal polisher.
Take the round sheet of tin,
dip it in soap emulsion,
then place it centrally in the press.
We obtain the soup pot.
The soup pot.
Soup pot.
Grosz, Mrs. Grosz, stay together.
Sir, I have 10 work permits here
for the Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik
(German Enamel Factory)
cosigned by Mr. Bankier and myself.
If it's carbonized,
clean it with a file.
But don't touch both the
electrodes at the same time.
You'll get electrocuted.
Here, have a try.
Roll the metal under the press,
but be very careful unless
you want your fingers
to become part of the teapot.
Occupation?
I'm a writer. I play the flute.
But Moses is a skilled metalworker.
He can make tin pots.
He can make tanks.
He can make whatever
Mr. Schindler asks.
He's highly skilled. Give him your card.
Moses, give him your card.
Now, dip the basin with the
tongs into the enamel solution.
And after swivelling it around,
carefully place it aside to drip dry.
And whatever he asks you, allow me
just to represent
you and speak for you.
Don't say a word.
Filing, billing, keeping track
of my appointments, shorthand.
Typing, obviously.
How is your typing?
Uh, all right.
Please.
You need a secretary.
Pick one.
I don't know how.
They're all so qualified.
You have to choose.
Prosze sie ladnie usmiechac.
(Please give a nice smile).
Big smile. Big smile.
Uwaga.
(Attention).
If you would, look after my guest.
Boxed teas are good. Coffee, pate,
kielbasa sausage,
cheeses, Beluga caviar.
-Yes.
-And, of course,
who could live without
German cigarettes?
Get me as many as you can find.
And some more fresh fruit.
The real rarities, oranges,
lemons, pineapples.
I need several boxes of Cuban cigars.
The best.
Yes. And dark, unsweetened chocolate.
Not in the shape of lady
fingers, the chunk chocolate.
Big as my hand, you
sample at wine tastings.
Yes.
We're going to need lots of cognac.
The best, Hennessy.
Dom Perignon champagne.
Get L'Espadon sardines,
and, oh, try to find nylon stockings.
It is my distinct pleasure to announce
the fully operational status
of Deutsche Emailwarenfabrik.
Patrz jakies szmaty! (See some rags!)
Manufacturers of superior
enamelware crockery,
expressly designed and
crafted for military use.
Utilizing only the
most modern equipment,
D.E.F.'s staff of highly skilled and
experienced artisans and journeymen
deliver a product of
unparalleled quality,
enabling me to proffer, with
absolute confidence and pride,
a full line of field and kitchenware
unsurpassable in all
respects by my competitors.
See attached list and
available colours.
Anticipating the enclosed bids
will meet with your approval
and looking forward to a long and
mutually prosperous association,
I extend to you in advance
my sincerest gratitude
and very best regards.
Oskar Schindler.
Yeah, I need 700 gross from
here for next Thursday.
Nine hundred, no, make
it 10 for Wednesday.
All this stuff here goes to Madritsch's
factory on Tuesday of next week.
My father was fond of saying,
'You need three things in life,
a good doctor,
a forgiving priest,
and a clever accountant.'
The first two,
I've never had much use for.
But the third...
Just pretend, for Christ's sake.
Is that all?
I'm trying to thank you.
I'm saying I couldn't have
done this without you.
The usual thing would be to
acknowledge my gratitude.
It would also, by the way,
be the courteous thing.
You're welcome.
Get out of here.
Klonowska, who is it?
She's so embarrassed. Look at her.
You know something? You would like her.
-Oskar, please.
-What?
I don't have to like her
just because you do.
You would, though.
It doesn't work that way.
You've done well here.
You look wonderful.
Be careful of the step, miss.
Mrs. Schindler, Marek.
It's not a charade, all this?
A charade? How could it be a charade?
The clothes, the car, the apartment.
Wait a minute.
Take a guess how many
people are on my payroll.
Oskar.
My father, at the height of his
success, had 50. I've got 350.
Three hundred and fifty workers
on the factory floor, with one purpose.
To make pots and pans?
To make money.
For me.
Does anyone ask about me?
Back home?
Everybody.
All the time.
Hmm.
They won't soon forget the name
Schindler here, I can tell you that.
'Oskar Schindler,' they'll say.
'Everybody remembers him.'
'He did something extraordinary.'
'He did something no one else did.'
'He came here with nothing,'
a suitcase,
'and built a bankrupt company
into a major manufactory.'
'And left with a steamer trunk.'
'Two steamer trunks full of money.'
'All the riches of the world.'
Hmm.
It's comforting to see
that nothing's changed.
You're wrong, Emilie.
There's no way I could
have known this before,
but there was always something missing.
Something was missing.
Even if I'd known what it was,
there's nothing I could have
done about it, because...
you can't create this thing.
And it makes all the difference in the
world between success and failure.
Luck?
War.
Should I stay?
It's a beautiful city.
I asked you if I should stay.
It's up to you.
Promise me, Oskar,
no doorman or maitre
d' will ever presume
I'm anyone other than Mrs. Schindler,
and I'll stay.
Goodbye, darling.
I could try to read this, or I could
eat my lunch while it's still hot.
We're doing well?
-Yes.
-Better this month than last?
Yes.
Any reason to think next
month will be worse?
The war could end.
What?
There is a machinist outside
who'd like to thank you
personally for giving him a job.
Every day he comes.
He's very grateful. It'll
just take a minute.
Mr. Lowenstein?
I want to thank you, sir,
for giving me the opportunity to work.
You're welcome. I'm sure
you're doing a great job.
The SS beat me up. They
would have killed me,
but I am essential to the
war effort, thanks to you.
That's great.
I work hard for you.
I'm sure you do.
I'll continue to work hard for you.
That's great. Thanks.
God bless you, sir.
All right.
You are a good man.
He saved my life.
Yes, he did.
God bless him.
Yeah. Come on.
God bless you.
I'm sorry, Herr Direktor, but
you're running very late.
This is for the
Obersturmbannfuhrer, sir.
And this is for his niece, Greta.
It's her birthday.
By the way...
Greta as in Garbo.
don't ever do that to me again.
Go, go, drive!
Don't bow.
Did you happen to notice that
that man had one arm?
Did he?
What's his use?
Very useful.
How?
Very useful! Success!
Besen und Schaufeln werden ausgeladen
(Brooms and shovels have been unloaded)
jeder nimmt sich eine und dann wird die Strase gereinigt.
(Each one takes one and cleans the streets).
We'll be late for work.
You shouldn't think of
them as yours, Oskar.
You need to understand that
some of the officers here
don't give a damn about production.
To them, it's a matter of...
national priority that Jews
be made to shovel snow.
It's got nothing to do
with reality, Oskar.
You know it and I know it.
Jews shovelling snow,
it's got a ritual significance.
Come with me.
I am an essential worker.
Essential worker?
Yes.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Essential worker for Oskar Schindler.
A one-armed Jew? Twice as useless!
-Yes, yes.
-Twice as useless!
I lost a day of production, Rolf.
I work for Oskar Schindler.
Danka, look at the snow. Look at the snow.
Look at the snow!
I lost a worker.
I expect to be compensated.
File a grievance with
the Economic Office.
It's your right.
Would it do any good?
Of course not.
A big shot from the SS Budget and
Construction Office came to lunch,
and he told us that to believe...
the Jewish skilled
worker had a place in...
Reich economics was a treasonable idea.
A one-armed machinist, Oskar?
He was a metal press operator.
Quite skilled.
Herr Direktor?
Shit. I don't believe it.
Stern, is that you?
No, it's Poldek.
It's about Stern.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Given name first, then your surname.
Do not bring your baggage with you.
It will follow you later.
Leave your luggage on the platform.
Clearly label it.
Lassen Sie Ihr Gepack am Bahnsteig.
(Leave your luggage on the platform).
Stern?
He's on the list.
He is?
Well, let's find him.
I'm sorry. You can't have him.
He's on the list.
If he were an essential worker
he would not be on the list.
I'm talking to a clerk.
What is your name?
Sir, the list is correct.
I didn't ask you about the list.
I asked you your name.
Klaus Tauber.
Tauber.
Hauptscharfuhrer,
this gentleman thinks a
mistake's been made.
My plant manager is
somewhere on this train.
If it leaves with him on it,
it'll disrupt production
and the Armaments Board
will want to know why.
Achtung, dieser Zug fahrt jetzt ab.
(Attention, the train is leaving now).
Is he on the list?
Yes, sir.
Itzhak Stern.
Well,
the list is correct, sir.
There is nothing I can do.
What is your name?
Close and secure all doors.
My name?
-My name is Kunder.
-This train is now leaving.
Kunder. Hauptscharfuhrer Kunder.
K-U-N-D-E-R. And what's yours?
Schindler. S-C-H-I-N-D-L-E-R.
Gentlemen, thank you very much.
I think I can guarantee you
you'll both be in Southern Russia
before the end of the month. Good day.
Zamykac dokladnie drzwi.
(Close the door properly).
Dokladnie zamykac drzwi.
Stern!
Stern! Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern! Itzhak Stern!
Stern! Stern!
Itzhak Stern!
Stern!
Sir?
-Stern!
-Herr Direktor.
My apologies.
Stop the train!
I apologize.
He's here!
Stop the train!
Stop the train! Stop it!
Sign here.
Initial there.
Makes no difference to
us, you understand.
This one, that one.
It's the inconvenience to the list.
It's the paperwork.
I somehow left my work card at home.
I tried to explain them
it was a mistake, but...
I'm sorry, it was stupid!
What if I got here five minutes later?
Then where would I be?
I woke up from a dream this morning.
I was broke and sharing a room
with 12 people I didn't know,
only to discover I was
broke and sharing
a room with 12 people I didn't know.
You laugh about it?
I have to laugh.
You are living behind walls.
The walls I can deal with.
It's the restrictions to
my life I'm tired of.
Those walls keep them out.
That's all I care about.
I like it here.
There's a kind of, I don't know,
ancestral squalor to it all.
-You are a slave to these people.
-No one envies us anymore.
I'm smart.
Oh, yes, you're smart.
You're a real genius.
You had your chance.
Today, today I actually found
time to organize a thought.
I can't remember
the last time I did that.
When's the last time we did this?
When's the last time
we stood around and talked?
No one ordered me onto a truck today.
No one took my business away from me.
You don't really
have a business to take.
There's nowhere down from here.
This is it.
This is the bottom.
The ghetto is liberty.
This street divides the ghetto
just about in half.
Right side, Ghetto A,
civil employees,
industrial workers, and so on.
Left side, Ghetto B,
surplus labour,
the elderly and infirm, mostly.
Which is where you will want to start.
Do you have any questions, sir?
Ja, why is the top down?
I'm fucking freezing.
We expect a labour
force of 25,000 to 30,000.
Segregated, of course.
The men in the barracks
near the quarry.
The women on
the other side of the wire.
My place is where?
There, sir.
-There?
-Yes, the villa.
You call that a villa?
Their synagogue, can you see it?
That's not a villa.
We're planning to turn it
into the camp stables.
It's a house.
What's that over there?
Kindergarten.
Fifty-one.
And we have a dentist,
shoemaker, practical physicians.
There they are, sir.
Hmm.
One of you is a very lucky girl.
There is...
an opening for a job...
away from all this...
backbreaking work...
at my new villa.
Uh...
Which of you has domestic experience?
Ja, on second thought, I don't
really want someone else's maid.
All those annoying
habits I have to undo.
I don't want to give you my cold.
What's your name?
-Helen Hirsch.
-What?
Helen Hirsch.
What? I can't hear.
Ja.
Take it all down!
To work!
Take it down!
It is not safe!
She says the foundation was poured wrong.
She's got to take it down.
I told her it's the barracks,
not the fucking Hotel Europa.
Fucking Jew bitch engineer.
You fucking bitch!
Herr Kommandant.
The entire foundation
has to be torn
down and re-poured.
If not, there will be
at least a subsidence
at the southern end of the barracks.
Subsidence,
and then collapse.
-And you are an engineer?
-Yes.
My name is Diana Reiter.
I'm a graduate of civil engineering
from the University of Milan.
An educated Jew,
like Karl Marx himself.
-Unterscharfuhrer!
-Jawohl? (Yes?)
Shoot her.
What?
Herr Kommandant,
I'm only trying to do my job.
Ja, I'm doing mine.
But, sir, she's
foreman of construction.
We are not going to have
arguments with these people.
Okay.
No. Shoot her here,
on my authority.
It will take more than that.
I'm sure you're right.
Take it down, re-pour it,
rebuild it.
Like she said.
We have more to see, but we have
only one more hour of light.
Today is history.
Today will be remembered.
Years from now,
the young will ask with
wonder about this day.
Today is history,
and you are part of it.
Six hundred years ago,
when elsewhere they were
footing the blame for the Black Death,
Kazimierz the Great...
...so-called,
told the Jews they
could come to Krakow.
They came.
Not that fat. No, less.
They trundled their
belongings into the city.
Yes, a bit less.
They settled.
They took hold.
They prospered...
in business, science,
education, the arts.
They came here with nothing.
Nothing.
And they flourished.
For six centuries there
has been a Jewish Krakow.
Think about that.
By this evening,
those six centuries are a rumour.
They never happened.
Today is history.
Absitzen und in Zweierreihen antreten!
(Spread out and enter in two rows!)
Kameraden! Schneller!
(Comrades! Quickly!)
I think we will start with Ghetto B.
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
All right?
Start from both sides?
-No, no, I would like you to start there.
-The right side?
-The right side, yeah.
-And then move around.
All right.
Aufmachen!
(Open!)
Lakoom.
(Get up).
-Mitacht la meeta. (Quite a bit).
-Bohow. (Oh).
Hopp, hopp, hopp, hopp!
Runterkommen!
(Come down!)
Rauskommen, Juden!
(Get down, Jews!)
Nach platz!
(To the square!)
Gold, Chaim!
Platz Chodi. (Chodi Square).
Yes, Chaim Gold.
Shoot him.
Nie zabijaj! Nie zabijaj!
(Do not kill! Do not kill!)
Ziehen Sie warme Kleidung...
(Put warm clothes)
an und begeben Sie sich zum Platz...
(and go to the square...)
Keine Koffer! Keine Koffer!
(No suitcases! No suitcases!)
Gehen Sie durch!
(Walk through!)
Keine Koffer! Keine Koffer!
(No suitcases! No suitcases!)
Hey, little boy.
Wie alt bist du, he? (How old are you, eh?)
Na, wie heist du?
(What is your name?)
Wie heist du, eh?
(What is your name, eh?)
Keine Koffer, hab ich gesagt!
(No suitcases, I said!)
Packt keine Koffer! Keine Koffer!
(Do not pack suitcases! No suitcases!)
Ruber zum Platz Chodi!
(Go the Chodi Square!)
Koffer hier lassen! (Leave
you suitcases here!)
Blauschein. (Blue cards)
Platz Chodi! (Chodi Square!)
Was soll der Koffer hier?
(What is this suitcase for?)
Alles ruber zum Platz Chodi!
(All go to Chodi Square)
We're getting out through the sewers.
I have to check if they're clear.
Mila, pack some things.
Nothing bigger than this.
I can't go in the sewers. I told
you I won't go in the sewers.
You can go.
Yes, you can.
I won't go in the sewers.
Move! Over there!
Over there! Move!
Your card, Jew!
Keine Papiere, Jude!
(No papers, Jew!)
That line.
Deine Karte!
(Your card!)
Ich geh nicht rauf...
(I am not going up...)
wegen Deiner verdammten Karte!
(because of your damn card!)
Deine Scheis karte!
(Your shit card!)
Was soll denn die Scheise?
(What is this shit?)
Bist du denn verruckt geworden?
(Are you crazy?)
Mit diesem Scheisgewehr...
(With this gun...)
hattest du mich erschiesen konnen!
you could have killed me!)
Du hast so nah an mir vorbeigeschossen!
(You were so close to me!)
Was heist hier Entschuldigung?
(What is the excuse here?)
Du bist wohl Verruckt ge Worden!
(You're probably crazy!)
Zuruckbleiben! Zuruckbleiben!
(Stay back! Stay back!)
Nicht sprechen, nicht sprechen!
(Do not speak, do not speak!)
Einfach zu den Lastwagen gehen!
(Just go to the trucks!)
Weiterlaufen!
(Continue running!)
Weiterlaufen! Nicht sprechen
(Continue running! Do not speak!)
Komm her, du Judensau!
(Come here, you Jewish pig!)
Bleib stehen, hab ich gesagt. Bleib stehen!
(Stay, I said. Stay!)
Chodzcie tu szybko!
(Walk here fast!)
She's good as dead.
Leave her.
Give me a moment.
Just let me bring her inside.
You can join her...
or join the line.
Women to the left!
-Wilhelm!
-Rose!
Men to right. Women to the left.
Women to the left.
Let me go! I won't leave my husband!
Women to the left,
Promise me, be safe.
and men to the right.
Your government is
in the wrong country!
Mama! Mama!
Mila!
You have a Blauschein (Blue card).
Blauschein (Blue card)
doesn't matter anymore,
they are cleaning out the ghetto.
There is not enough room for you.
What are you talking about?
We tried it before. There's
more than enough room.
I changed my mind!
Mama!
Oh, look at the space in there.
Now look at me.
You are just scared.
I can fit the girl, but not you.
Mama, I'm coming out!
Stay where you are.
I'd rather you be here
than who knows where.
Mama!
Herr Kommandant!
Very good saluting.
I respectfully report
I've been given orders
to clear the bundles from the road,
so there will be no obstructions
to the thoroughfare.
Finish and join the
lines, little Polish...
clicking soldier.
Mrs. Dresner?
Yes.
Oh, you are a friend of my son's.
Don't worry, I'll go quietly.
I'll be no trouble.
No, get under the stairs.
They'll be done searching soon.
You'll be safe there.
Please hide. Please.
...warmed by the sun.
Hide under the stairs.
I've searched the building.
There's no one here.
Also, gehen wir zum nachsten Block.
(So, let's go to the next block).
Einverstanden.
(Agreed).
Danka!
Mama!
Hello, Adam.
Hello, Danka.
Come with me. I will
put you in the good line.
Do you know the saying, 'An
hour of life is still life'?
You are not a boy anymore.
I'm saying a blessing for you.
Oh, please, let's go.
Let's go, please.
Come on.
Markieren.
(Mark here)
Nie! Prosze pana, niech pan...
(No! Please, sir...)
...nie znajdziemy!
(... we will not find it!)
Was ist das? Ist das Bach?
(What is this? Is it Bach?)
Nein, nein. Mozart.
(No, no. Mozart)
-Mozart?
-Ja. (Yes).
Das wollen wir heute noch schaffen?
(We still want to do that today?)
Nee, schaffen wir nie.
(No, we never allow proximity).
I wish this fucking night were over.
Appell! Funferreihen!
(Roll call! Rows of five!)
Antreten!
(Line up)
Halt, alle anstellen!
(Stop, everbody stop!)
Los, los, Funferreihen!
(Go, go, rows of five!)
Mutzen ab!
(Hats off!)
Namen verlesen!
(Read the names!)
Wer aufgerufen wird, hebt seine hand...
(Whoever is called raises his hand...)
und ein deutliches Jawohl!
(with a clear yes!)
Jawohl.
(Yes).
-Keller, Fanni!
-Jawohl. (Yes).
-Adalbert, Hermann!
-Faber, Dorothea!
-Jawohl. (Yes).
-Goldstein, Pola!
-Warmberger, Markus!
-Jawohl. (Yes).
Edelstein, Max!
Appell antreten!
(Roll call over!)
Do pracy!
(To work!)
The worst is over.
We are workers now.
Keine Mudigkeit vorschutzen!
(Do not pretend tiredness!)
Oh, God, Amon.
Sofort in der Baracke zuruckmelden!
(Return to the barracks immediately!)
Komm du mal schon her! Komm du schon!
(You come here in order! Come here in order.)
Na komm! Na komm!
(Now come! Now come!)
Amon, you're such a
damned fucking child!
Wakey, wakey.
Make coffee.
Make it yourself.
The SS will manage certain
industries itself
inside Plaszow.
A metalworks, brush factory,
another for reprocessing
Jewish clothing
from the ghettos for use by
bombed-out families back home.
But it's private industry like
yours that stands to benefit most
by moving inside the wire of
Commandant Amon Goeth's camp...
No, no, no. Sit, sit.
Julian, how are you?
Good to see you, my friend.
-Oskar Schindler.
-Leo John.
Franz, good to see you.
Hello, Oskar.
Glad you could join us.
My pleasure. My pleasure.
-Julius. How are you? Good, good.
-You lost weight.
Only in the shoulders. Please,
everybody, sit down. Sit down.
How are you doing?
Oskar Schindler.
We started without you.
Fine. I Miss anything good?
I was explaining to Herr Bosch
and Herr Madritsch
some of the benefits of moving
their factories into Plaszow.
I meant the food.
Since your labour
is housed on-site,
it's available to you at all times.
You can work them
all night if you want.
Your factory policies,
whatever they've been in the
past, they'll continue to be.
They'll be respected.
I have to know, where do
you get a suit like that?
What is that? Is that silk?
Of course.
Ja.
It has a nice sheen about it.
Thank you.
Very nice.
I'd say I'd get you one, but the
man who made it is probably dead.
I don't know.
I go to work the other day.
Nobody's there.
Nobody tells me about this. I have
to find out. I have to go in.
Everybody's gone.
No.
They're not gone.
They're here.
They're mine!
Every day that goes
by, I'm losing money.
Every worker that is
shot costs me money.
I have to find somebody else.
I have to train them.
We are going to be making so much money
that none of this is going to matter.
It's bad business.
Thank you.
Leave the bottle.
Take that.
Lena,
thank you.
Scherner told me something
else about you.
Yeah? What's that?
That you know the meaning of the word
'gratitude.'
That it's not some vague thing with you
like it is with others.
You want to stay where you are.
You've got things going on the side.
Things are good.
You don't want anybody
telling you what to do.
I can understand all that, you know.
I know you.
What you want...
is your own sub-camp.
Do you have any idea what is involved?
The paperwork alone, and then you've
got to build the fucking thing.
Getting the fucking permits
is enough to drive you crazy.
Then the engineers show up,
they stand around, they argue
about drainage, foundations,
codes, exact specifications,
parallel fences four kilometres long,
1,200 kilograms of barbed wire,
6,000 kilograms of electrified
fences, ceramic insulators,
three cubic meters of
air space per prisoner.
I'm telling you, you
want to shoot somebody.
I've been through it, you know? I know.
Well, you know. You've been through it.
You could make things easier for me.
I'd be grateful.
Aus dem Weg da!
(Out of the way!)
Weitergehen! Weitergehen!
(Keep moving! Keep moving!)
Where's Stern?
Goldberg and Chilowicz,
make sure I see my cut
from the factory owners in this camp.
Leaving you to take care
of my main account,
the Schindler account.
He wants his independence.
I gave it to him.
But independence costs money.
This, you understand?
Look at me.
Don't forget who you
are working for now.
Jawohl!
Make sure he stays. He's
a slippery bastard!
We need more wine.
More wine!
Stand on my friend.
Don't let him leave.
Was passiert denn in meinem Leben
(What happens in my life)
Prost! Prost!
(Cheers! Cheers!)
Thank you, Herr Direktor.
Prost, Herr Direktor!
What are you doing?
What? Scratching my head.
Makes them think we have lice. Helps
make them keep their distance.
-Do you have lice?
-Do you have your notebook?
The calendar on my
desk has the birthdays
of our SS friends' wives and children.
Don't forget to send something.
Record pay-offs to the
Main Administration
and Economics Office, the Arm...
Slowly, Stern, slowly.
The Armaments Board, Governor
General's Division of the Interior
and Chief of Police as 'fees.'
And make them on the
first of each month,
as opposed to individual
pay-offs to our SS contacts.
The list is in the lower drawer
of my desk, which you...
'First of month...'
SS contacts list, lower drawer
of my desk, which you handle
as cash contributions
to legitimate charities
sent, of course, to
each official's office.
Dealings with our black market contacts
listed as suppliers in
the legitimate ledger
-are more complicated.
-Forget it.
What do you mean, forget it?
You can't forget it.
It gives me a headache.
It gives me a headache!
-I couldn't get you out of here.
-I'll be all right.
Anyway, I'm here almost every week.
Wednesdays, usually.
I'll look in on you,
see how you're doing.
Here,
put these in your pocket.
Come on.
Herr Direktor,
don't let things fall apart.
I've worked too hard.
Thanks for...
Good luck.
Achtung, Mutzen ab!
(Attention, hats off!)
-Work!
-An die Arbeit! (Get to work!)
What are you making?
Hinges, sir.
I've got some
workers coming in tomorrow.
Where the hell they from again?
Yugoslavia, Herr Kommandant.
I've got to make room.
Make me a hinge.
Yes, sir.
Keep going, you're doing well.
Oh, that's very good.
But I'm a bit confused,
and perhaps you can help me.
What I don't understand is...
that you've been working
since I think, what, about...
6:00 this morning?
Yet,
such a small pile of hinges.
-Oh, Christ.
-May I try that, sir?
Check the angle lever.
Maybe it's bent.
No, no. You wouldn't hear a click
if the angle lever hits the pin.
Maybe it's the pin.
Maybe the pin shaft is greasy.
Ja, come on.
What did I just say? Here.
Herr Kommandant.
I beg to report that
my heap of hinges...
was so unsatisfactory
because the machines
were being recalibrated this morning.
I was put on to shovelling coal.
Strange, huh?
Yeah.
Thank you, Muek.
Ah, Lisiek.
Don't touch the leather,
it's just been oiled.
-Rottenfuhrer.
-Oh, for me?
Oh, thank you very much, Herr Direktor.
Herr Direktor!
Herr Direktor.
He was making hinges slowly.
So the man can turn out a hinge in
less than a minute.
Why the long story?
Hmm?
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Nobody knows who
stole the chicken, hmm?
Tell him about the chicken.
A man walks around with a chicken
and nobody notices this.
Save yourselves.
Tell him about the chicken.
Still nobody knows.
It was you.
You committed this crime.
No, sir.
But you know who, though.
-Yes.
-Who?
Him!
He's very gifted.
Yeah, sure.
Bring him over.
Sir.
Thank you.
Thank you again, Herr Direktor.
You're welcome again.
It's an honour to work for
such a great company.
It's great to have you.
I promise to learn everything there is
to know about enamelware production.
That's great.
Hello?
-Miss Elsa Krause is here.
-I only need five minutes.
She wants to speak to
the Herr Direktor.
Yes.
He won't see you.
Please, sit down.
Pernod? Cognac?
No. No, thank you.
So, what can I do for you?
They say that no one dies here.
They say your factory is a haven.
They say you are good.
Who says that?
Everyone.
My name is Regina
Perlman, not Elsa Krause.
I've been living in Krakow on false
papers since the ghetto massacre.
My parents are in Plaszow.
Their names are Chana
and Jakob Perlman.
They are older people.
They are killing older
people now in Plaszow.
They bury them up in the forest. Look,
I don't have any money.
I borrowed these clothes.
I'm begging you.
Please.
Please bring them here.
I don't do that.
You've been misled.
I ask one thing.
Whether or not the worker
has certain skills.
That's what I ask and
that's what I care about.
My father is an importer,
not a metalworker.
Such activities are illegal.
You will not entrap me!
Cry, and I will have you arrested.
I swear to God!
People die.
It's a fact of life.
He wants to kill everybody?
Great!
What am I supposed to do about it?
Bring everybody over?
Is that what you think?
Send them over to Schindler.
Send them all!
His place is a haven, didn't you know?
It's not a factory.
It's not an enterprise of any kind.
It's a haven for rabbis and orphans
and people with no skills whatsoever!
You think I don't
know what you're doing?
You're so quiet all the time.
I know, I know!
-Are you losing money?
-No I'm not losing money.
That's not the point!
So the point is?
It's dangerous!
It's dangerous to me!
You have to understand. Goeth
is under enormous pressure.
You have to think of
it in his situation.
He's got this whole place to run.
He's responsible for everything
here, all these people.
He's got a lot of
things to worry about.
And he's got the war
which brings out the worst in people.
Never the good, always the bad.
Always the bad.
But in normal circumstances he wouldn't
be like this. He'd be all right.
There'd just be the good
aspects of him, which...
He's a wonderful crook.
A man who loves good food, good
wine, the ladies, making money...
Killing.
He can't enjoy it.
Bejski told me the other day,
somebody escaped
from a work detail outside the wire.
Goeth lined up everybody from
the missing man's barracks.
He shot the man to the left of Bejski,
the man to the right of him.
He walked down the line shooting
every other man with a pistol.
Twenty-five.
What do you want me to do about it?
Nothing, nothing.
We're just talking.
'Perlman.'
Perlman!
Husband and wife.
Jakob and Chana Perlman!
Have Goldberg bring them over.
Mutzen ab!
(Hats off!)
Appell abtreten!
(At ease!)
I'm sure this will be better
than those rags, Lisiek.
Herr Direktor, I was just helping
Lisiek to find something
to clean the stains from the
Herr Kommandant's bathtub.
Go clean it.
Pardon me, Herr Direktor.
You don't have to report to me, Helen.
You know who I am?
Hmm?
I'm Schindler.
Of course. I have heard, and
you have been here before.
Here, why don't you
keep this some place?
Go on, take it.
I get extra food here.
Well, if you don't want
to eat it, trade it.
Or give it to Lisiek.
Why not build yourself up?
My first day here,
he beat me because I threw
out the bones from dinner.
He came down to the basement
at midnight, and he...
he asked me where they were.
For his dogs,
you understand.
I said to him, I...
I don't know how I say this.
I never could say it
now, I said to him,
'Why are you beating me?'
He said, 'The reason I beat you now'
is because you ask why I beat you.'
I know your sufferings, Helen.
It doesn't matter.
I have accepted them.
Accepted them?
One day he will shoot me.
No, no, no, he won't shoot you.
I know.
I see things.
We were on the roof on Monday,
young Lisiek and I, and we saw...
the Herr Kommandant come
out of the from door and
down the steps by the patio,
right there below us,
and there on the steps
he drew his gun and he
shot a woman who was passing by.
A woman carrying a bundle.
Through the throat.
Just a woman on her way
somewhere, you know?
She was no...
fatter or thinner or...
slower or faster than anyone else,
and I couldn't guess what had she done.
The more you see...
of the Herr Kommandant, the
more you see there is no...
set rules that you can live by.
You can't say to yourself, 'If I
follow these rules, I will be safe.'
He won't shoot you because
he enjoys you too much.
He enjoys you so much he won't
even let you wear the star.
He doesn't want anyone else to know
it's a Jew he's enjoying.
He shot the woman from the steps
because she meant nothing to him.
She was one of a series,
neither offending or pleasing him.
But you, Helen.
It's all right.
It's not that kind of a kiss.
Thank you.
Shh.
Here.
Right. The wine.
Wonderful party, Amon.
Thank you.
Why do you drink that motor oil?
Hmm? I send you good
stuff all the time.
Your liver's going to explode
like a hand grenade.
You know, I look at you.
I watch you.
You're never drunk.
Oh, that's...
that's real control.
Control is power.
That's power.
Is that why they fear us?
We have the fucking power to
kill, that's why they fear us.
They fear us because we have
the power to kill arbitrarily.
A man commits a crime,
he should know better.
We have him killed, and we
feel pretty good about it.
Or we kill him ourselves
and we feel even better.
That's not power, though.
That's justice.
It's different than power.
Power...
is when we have every
justification to kill,
and we don't.
You think that's power?
That's what the emperors had.
A man stole something,
he's brought in before the emperor,
he throws himself down on the
ground, he begs for mercy.
He knows he's going to die.
And the emperor...
pardons him.
This worthless man.
He lets him go.
I think you are drunk.
That's power, Amon.
That is power.
Amon the Good.
I pardon you.
What do they want?
I don't know, but they're in my
office now reviewing our books.
As my accountant,
tell me, should I be
alarmed that the auditors
-are reviewing my books?
-Well...
Or have you done your job properly?
You needn't be alarmed.
I needn't be alarmed.
I'm sorry, sir.
Do you know how much
this saddle is worth?
Do you know how much it costs?
All right.
Stern, what the hell are you
doing following me around?
Baracken eins, elf
(Barracks one, eleven)
funfzehn und zwounddreisig am Appellplatz melden.
(fifteen and thirty-two at the Parade gorund).
She was smoking on the job.
Tell her not to do it again.
I have to report, sir.
I've been unable to remove
the stains from your bathtub.
What are you using, Lisiek?
Soap, Commandant.
Soap? Not lye?
Go ahead, go on, leave.
Leave, I pardon you.
I pardon you.
Although I am not a
rabbi, in these circumstances
I pray to the Almighty
that he will forgive me
if I intone the blessings.
So...
This is where you come to hide from me.
I came to tell you
that you really are a wonderful cook
and a well-trained servant.
I mean it,
if you need a reference after the war, dear,
I'd be happy to give you one.
It must get lonely down here
when you're listening to everyone
upstairs having such a good time.
Does it?
You can answer.
But what's the right answer?
That's what you're thinking.
What does he want to hear?
The truth,
Helen, is always the right answer.
Yes, you're right.
Sometimes we're both lonely.
Yes. I...
I mean,
I would like so much to
reach out...
and touch you in your loneliness.
What would that be like,
I wonder? I mean...
What would be wrong with that?
I realize that you're not...
a person in the strictest
sense of the word, but...
No, maybe you're right about
that too, you know, maybe...
what's wrong isn't...
It's not us.
It's... no, it's this.
I mean, when they compare you to
vermin, and to rodents, and to lice...
I just...
No, you make a good point.
You make a very good point.
Is this the face of a rat?
Are these the eyes of a rat?
Hath not a Jew eyes?
Ci wszystko wybaczy
(You will forgive everything)
Bo milosc moj mily
(Because my love is so sweet)
I feel...
for you, Helen.
To ja.
(It's me.)
No, I don't think so.
You're a Jewish bitch.
You nearly talked me
into it, didn't you?
Didn't you?
Bravo.
Hoch! Hoch! Hoch!
(High! High! High!)
-Bravo!
Hoch! Hoch! Hoch!
(High! High! High!)
On behalf of the workers, sir,
I wish for you a happy birthday.
Happy birthday
Well, the staff, please.
Thank you very much for the lovely cake.
Thank you very much. Tell
them thank you from me.
The trains arrived and the people
were driven out with clubs.
They were lined up in front
of two big warehouses.
One was marked 'Cloak Room,'
and the other 'Valuables.'
And there they were made to undress.
A Jewish boy handed them pieces of
string to tie their shoes together.
They shaved their hair.
They told them it was needed to
make something special
for U-boat crews.
And then they were...
herded down a big corridor
to bunkers with Stars
of David on the doors
and signs that said 'Bath
and Inhalation Room.'
SS gave them soap.
They told them to breathe all the time
because it's good for disinfecting.
And then they gassed them.
Mila, why soaps?
So that they would agree
to go in, I think.
Come on, Mila, stop it.
Your bedtime stories
are scaring everyone.
Yeah.
You know it's ridiculous.
I cannot believe it.
I didn't say I believed it.
I said I heard it.
From who?
From somebody who heard it
from someone who was there.
You know,
if they were there,
they would have been gassed.
Yes.
It doesn't make any sense.
We're their workforce.
What sense does it make to
kill your own workforce?
To go to all this trouble of
assembling a workforce only to...
No, it can't be true.
We are very, very important for them.
Yeah, we do now. Good night.
Good night.
Good night. Sweet dreams.
Attention, attention.
Everyone who is alive
is to come to the Appellplatz.
Attention, attention.
We have to go to the Appellplatz.
Everyone who is alive...
The list makers are here.
...is to come to the Appellplatz.
There is going to be a selection.
Attention, attention.
Everyone who is alive
is to come to the Appellplatz.
Meine Herren.
(Gentlemen).
-Raz! (One!)
-Dwa! (Two!)
...die Hunderttausend Ungarn kommen...
(... hundreds of thousands of Hungarians are coming...)
Alle in einer Einzelreihe aufstellen!
(All line up in a single row!)
You could afford to
lose some weight, Amon.
And you've got to cut
down on the cognac.
Morning.
What's going on?
It's another semi-annual physical.
There.
Oh, I've...
got another shipment coming in of...
What are they this time?
Hungarians.
Ja, Hungarians.
We've got to separate the sick
from the healthy to make room.
Teraz! Teraz!
(Now! Now!)
Guten Nacht Mutter.
(Good night Mother).
Guten Nacht.
(Good night)
Das darf nicht
(This is not allowed)
bis zum Abend dauern!
(until the evening!)
Let me help you.
Zack, zack, zack!
(Quick, quick, quick!)
We've got to go out there.
Don't go.
Look alive, Rebeka.
Guten Nacht Mutter.
(Good night mother).
Na okolo! Predzej! Predzej!
(Run around! Faster! Faster!)
Na okolo! Na okolo!
(Run around! Run around!)
Guten Nacht...
(Good night)
That's my mechanic.
Whose bright idea was
it to get rid of him?
Ruszaj sie! Naokolo!
(Move! Run around!)
Szybciej! Szybciej! Trzymaj ubrania!
(Hurry! Hurry! Keep your clothes!)
Guten Nacht
(Good night)
Otworz usta. Zajrzymy do gardla.
(Open your mouth. Let me see your throat.)
Wez gleboki oddech. Jeszcze. Jeszcze.
(Take a deep breath. Yes. Yes.)
Unies ramiona.
(Lift your arms).
Obroc sie.
(Turn around).
Przykucnij.
(Squat down)
Formowac kolmune!
(Form a column)
No, no, no. Wait, go away.
She can work.
Come here. Look,
separate the sick from the healthy.
Those who can work and those who can't.
She can work.
You can work, you can come.
Ruszac sie! Szybciej!
(Move! Hurry!)
Those not selected for transport,
put your clothes back on.
Go back to the barracks.
Return to the barracks.
Oh, my God!
Olek? Olek?
Danka?
Olek! Olek!
Olek?
Danka?
-Danka?
-Olek?
Ab in die Baracke!
(Get into the barrack!)
In die Baracke mit euch!
(Into the barrack!)
I didn't see him!
They're hiding. I'm telling
you, they're hiding.
I know Danka. She knows a good place.
She took all of them together.
Zuruck in die Baracken!
(Back to the barracks!)
Find your own hiding place. There's
no room for you here. Go away, quick!
Get out. This is our place. Get out!
Oskar!
Amon. Gentlemen.
Why didn't you call me?
I tried to call you. Here, Hujar, move.
Quite a picnic, huh? Madritsch. Oskar.
They're running a
little late, you know?
It's taking longer than I thought.
A drink?
Something cold. Bowle.
The Bowle.
Oh, another beautiful day.
Cisza! Spokoj!
(Silence! Quiet!)
Die Beladung der Transportwagen ist beendet.
(Loading of the transport wagons is finished).
Wir sind abfahrbereit.
(We are ready for departure).
Wody!
(Water!)
Wasser... Wasser.
(Water... Water).
Wohlsein.
(Well done).
Oh, thank you.
What do you say we get
your fire hoses out here
and hose down the cars? Thank you.
Indulge me.
-Hujar.
-Yes, sir.
Go bring the fire hoses.
Where's the fire?
In the windows.
That's it, that's it.
On the roof.
That's it, good, good. In
the window, in the window.
Come on. Come on.
That's it, more, more.
That's it, that's it.
More, more.
This is really cruel, Oskar.
You are giving them hope.
You shouldn't do that.
That's cruel!
Come on, try and reach
the far end. Look out.
Water! More water!
I've got some 200-meter hoses
back in Emalia.
I have 20 meters at home in my garden.
We can reach the cars at the end.
What?
Hujar.
Yeah, sure.
Don't forget the roof.
On the roof on the other side.
Scharfuhrer,
every time the train stops
you open the doors, you
give them water, yeah?
Jawohl.
(Yes).
This car! This car!
I'm not saying you'll
regret it, but you might.
You should be aware of that.
We will have to risk regret.
All right, sure. It's a nice day.
I'll go for a drive with you.
What about you?
I violated the Race
and Resettlement Act.
Though I doubt anyone can point
out the actual provision to me.
I kissed a Jewish girl.
Did your prick fall off?
He likes women.
He likes good-looking women.
He sees a beautiful
woman, he doesn't think.
I mean...
He has so many women.
And they love him.
Ja, they love him. I mean, he
is married, Ja, but he's...
All right, no.
She was Jewish. He
shouldn't have done it.
But you didn't see this girl.
I saw this girl. This girl was, woof...
She was very good-looking.
They cast a spell on
you, you know, the Jews.
When you work closely with
them, like I do, you see this.
They have this power.
It's like a virus.
Some of my men are
infected with this virus.
They should be pitied, not punished.
They should receive treatment.
This is as real as typhus.
I see this all the time.
It's a matter of money?
Hmm?
You're offering me a bribe?
A bribe? No.
No, please.
It's a gratuity.
Heil Hitler!
Hello, Amon.
Sit down.
We give you Jewish girls at
five marks a day, Oskar.
You should kiss us, not them.
God forbid you ever get a
real taste for Jewish skirt.
There's no future in it.
They don't have a future.
That's not just good,
old-fashioned, Jew-hating talk.
It's policy now.
Ja, schon gefangen! Gut!
(Yes, already caught! Good!)
Nochmal, ja! Schon!
(Again, yes! Nice!)
Also los! Bewegung!
(Let's go! Move!)
Schneller hier! Zack, zack, zack!
(Faster here! Quick, quick, quick!)
Beweg deinen Arsch!
(Move your ass!)
Das geht auch schneller!
(This is also a great success!)
Bewegt euch!
(Move!)
Schlaft nicht ein!
(Do not sleep!)
Nur die ganzen Fetzen, nicht das Gemuse!
(Only the whole scraps, not the vegetables!)
Komm, das kannst du mit den Handen machen,
(Come, you can do that with your hands,)
fass da vorn an!
(take the lead!)
Die Kleinteile lass liegen!
(Leave the small pieces!)
So ist es! Walhalla!
(That's the way it is! Walhalla!)
Walhalla ruft hier!
(Walhalla called here!)
Can you believe this?
As if I don't have enough to
do, they come up with this?
I have to find every rag
buried up here and burn it.
The party's over, Oskar.
They're closing
us down, sending
everybody to Auschwitz.
When?
I don't know. As soon as
I can arrange the shipments.
Maybe 30, 40 days.
That ought to be fun.
I've been talking to Goeth.
I know the destination.
These are the evacuation orders.
I'm to help organize the shipments,
put myself on the last train.
That's not what I was going to say.
I made Goeth promise me he'll
put in a good word for you.
Nothing bad is going
to happen to you there.
You'll receive special treatment.
The directives coming in from Berlin
mention 'special treatment'
more and more often.
I'd like to think
that's not what you mean.
Preferential treatment, all right?
Do we have to invent
a whole new language?
I think so.
You're staying, I take it.
In Krakow? What on Earth for?
What for? You have
a business to run.
Of course, you'll have to hire new workers.
Poles, I guess.
They cost a little more, but...
What are you going to do?
You ran my business.
No, I'm going home.
I've done what I came here for.
I've got more money than any
man can spend in a lifetime.
Some day,
this is all going to end, you know.
I was going to say
we'll have a drink then.
I think I better have it now.
Bible says And it still is news
Mama may have Papa may have
But God bless the child
That's got his own
Yes, the strong gets more
While the weak ones fade
Empty pockets don't ever make the grade
Mama may have Papa may have
But God bless the child
That's got his own
Money, you've got lots of friends
They're pounding on your...
I don't understand.
You want these people?
'These people'?
My people, I want my people.
Who are you, Moses?
Come on, what is this?
Where's the money in this?
Where's the scam?
It's good business.
It's good business in your opinion.
Look, you've got to move them,
the equipment,
everything to Czechoslovakia.
Pay for all that and
build another camp.
-Doesn't make any sense.
-Look, Amon...
-You're not telling me something.
-It's good for me.
I know them. I'm familiar with them.
I don't have to train them.
You're not telling me something.
It's good for you.
I'll compensate you.
That's right.
It's good for the army.
Yeah, of course.
-You know what I'm going to make?
-What?
-Artillery shells.
-Everyone's making artillery shells.
-Tank shells, they need that.
-Tanks shells, ja.
-Everybody's happy.
-Everyone's happy, except me.
You're probably scamming me somehow.
If I'm making 100,
you've got to be making 300.
And if you admit to 300,
then it's 400, actually.
But how?
I just told you.
You did, but you didn't.
Ja, all right, don't tell me.
I'll go along with it.
It's just irritating
I can't work it out.
Look,
all you have to do is tell
me what it's worth to you.
-What's a person worth to you?
-No, no, no, no.
What's one worth to you?
Poldek Pfefferberg.
Mila Pfefferberg.
And...
Uh... Stagel, Stagel...
Paul.
Paul Stagel.
Doctor.
The investors.
-I want all of them.
-Yes, sir.
Fischer. Ismail Fischer.
Fischer, Ismail.
Josef Scharf.
One moment, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Come on, Stern.
Scharf, Scharf.
The children.
All the children.
-Herbert Stier.
-Thank you.
How many?
Four hundred, 450.
More, more.
-Feigenbaum, Jakob.
-Wolf. Wolf Wein.
Feigenbaum, Lutek, Jakob... Nacha.
Yes? Nacha.
Nacha, that's right.
And Wolf.
How many?
600.
More.
You can do the same thing I'm doing.
You might even make money at it.
I don't know.
Come on, Julius, I know about the
extra food and clothes you give them.
Paid for out of your own pocket.
If we make a combined approach,
we could get more than
4,000 out, mine and yours.
Oskar...
We could relocate them in something
like safety, in Moravia.
I don't know.
How many cigarettes
have you smoked tonight?
Too many.
For every one...
you smoke, I smoke half.
I've done all I can.
I will not accept that.
No, Oskar, I can't do any more.
No.
How many? How many?
-850, give or take.
-Give or take what, Stern?
Give or take what? Count them.
How many?
That's it.
You can finish that page.
What did Goeth say about this?
You just told him how many
people you needed and...
You're not buying them.
You're buying them?
You're paying him for
each of these names?
If you were still working for me,
I'd expect you to talk me out of it.
It's costing me a fortune.
Finish the page and leave
one space at the bottom.
You...
The list is an absolute good.
The list is life.
All around its margins lies the gulf.
Oskar, there's a clerical error here
at the bottom of the last page.
No, there's one more name
I want to put there.
I'll never find a maid as well
trained as her at Brinnlitz.
They are all country girls.
No.
One hand of 21.
-If you win, I pay you 7,400 reichsmarks.
-No.
-Hit a natural, I make it 14,800.
If I win, the girl goes on my list.
I can't wager Helen in a card game.
Why not?
Wouldn't be right.
She's just going to Auschwitz
Number Two, anyway.
-What difference does it make?
-She's not going to Auschwitz.
I'd never do that to her.
No, I want her to come
back to Vienna with me.
I want her to come...
to work for me there.
I want to grow old with her.
Are you mad?
Amon,
you can't take her to Vienna with you.
No, of course I can't.
That's what I'd like to do.
What I can do,
if I'm any sort of a man,
is the next most merciful thing.
I shall take her into the woods and
shoot her painlessly
in the back of the head.
What was it you said for a...
natural 21?
Was it 14,800?
Schindlerjuden to these tables!
Say your names clearly.
We are the family Dresner.
Juda, Jonas, Donata, and Chaja.
We are Rosners. Henry, Manci and Leo.
-And our son.
-I am Olek.
Maria Mischel.
Chaim Nowak.
Wulkan, Markus.
Michael Lemper.
Itzhak Stern.
Rebeka and Joseph Bau.
-Rosalia Nussbaum.
-Wilhelm Nussbaum.
Jakob Levartov.
-Farber, Rosa.
-Farber, Andrzej.
Sara.
Friehof, Fischel.
Mietek Pemper.
Poldek and Mila Pfefferberg.
Horowitz, Dolek.
Adam Levy.
Marcel Goldberg.
Klipstein, Isak David.
Altmann, Eduard.
Grunberg, Miriam.
Luftig, Eliasz.
Hilmann, Eduard.
Erna Rothberg.
Zuckermann, Jetti.
Helen Hirsch.
The worst is over.
Men to this transport
and women to this transport.
Be careful.
Men to this transport and
women to this transport.
Watch your step. Men to this transport
and women to this transport.
Wonderful, Olek,
wonderful.
You know how we make ice into water?
Olek, get another one!
Alle in einer Einzelreihe aufstellen!
(All stand in a single row!)
You'll be pleased with the level
of efficiency I get from these workers.
Budzyn, under my command,
was the envy of every other
commandant in the labour camp system.
-The prisoners, however...
-Excuse me.
they would have rather
been somewhere else.
The train with the
women has already left Plaszow
and will be arriving here very shortly.
I know you've had a long journey.
But it's only a short walk
further to the factory,
where hot soup and
bread is waiting for you.
Welcome to Brinnlitz!
Beans in cholent?
Beans are the best part.
I don't like beans.
Beans and meat and potatoes and bread.
That's not the way you make cholent.
Eggs in cholent?
Yes!
I don't like cholent.
No, you don't.
What do you like?
I like caviar.
One day on the fire...
Alle vorm Wagen in Position bleiben.
(All cars are in position.)
Alle in der Gruppe zusammenbleiben.
(All stay together in the group.)
Wegbleiben vom Wagen!
(Stay away from the car!)
Wegbleiben vom Wagen, hab ich gesagt!
(Stay away from the car, I said!)
Schneller! Dalli, dalli, dalli!
(Faster! Quick, quick, quick!)
Was ist da hinten los!
(What's going on here!)
Schnell!
(Quick!)
Los, raus mit euch. Zack, zack, zack! Raus!
(Get out! Quick, Quick, quick! Out!)
Dreizig, funfunddreizig, vierzig, funfundvierzig.
(Thirty, thirty-five, forty, forty-five).
Aussteigen!
(Get out!)
Where are the list makers?
Where are the tables?
Raus mit euch!
(Get out!)
Hopp, hopp!
...bagaze w wagonach!
(...luggage in wagons!)
Dalli! Rausgehen! Schneller!
(Quick! Get out! Faster!)
Zostawcie bagaze w wagonach!
(Leave the luggage in the wagons!)
Schneller!
(Faster!)
Danka! Danka! Danka!
(Go faster!)
Mama, where are we?
They're in Auschwitz.
The train was never routed here.
A paperwork mistake.
Szybciej! Szybko!
(Hurry! Fast!)
Die Schuhe werfen!
(Remove your shoes!)
Schneller! Schneller!
(Faster! Faster!)
Ubrania skladac!
(Fold your clothing!)
Pod prysznic!
(To the shower!)
-Zieht euch aus! Bewegung!
(Remove your clothes! Move!)
Bewegt euch!
(Move!)
Stellt euch auf und zieht euch aus!
(Stand up and go out!)
-Rozbierac sie tam szybciej!
(Undress faster!)
Schneller!
(Faster!)
Szybko sie rozbierac.
(Undress quickly).
Dostaniecie mydlo I recznik...
(Get a soap and towel...)
I pojdziecie pod prysznic do dezynfeckji!
(and go to the shower for disinfection!)
Szybko sie rozbierac!
(Undress quickly).
Schneller!
(Faster!)
Zabierajcie to mydlo I szybko!
(Take that soap quickly!)
Zieht euch schneller aus! Bewegung!
(Move out faster! Move!)
Szybko! Szybko!
(Quickly! Quickly!)
Sofort hinein! Schneller!
(Get in immediately! Faster!)
Pojdziecie pod prysznic! Szybko!
(Into the shower! Quick!)
Schneller!
(Faster!)
Hinein zum Bad! Schneller!
(Into the bath! Faster!)
Schneller! Schneller!
(Faster! Faster)
Szybko! Szybko!
(Quickly! Quickly!)
Tu wchodzic!
(Come in!)
Blick hinunter!
(Look down!)
Die Hand auf die Schulter!
(Hand on the shoulder!)
How old are you, mother?
Sixty-eight.
Cough for me, mother.
They say to fall against
the fence is a kindness.
Don't kill yourself
against the fence, Clara.
If you do, you'll never know
what happened to you.
How old are you, mother?
Sixty-six, sir.
Sir?
Good morning.
A mistake has been made. We
are not supposed to be here.
We work for Oskar Schindler.
We are Schindler Jews.
Who is Oskar Schindler?
He had a factory in Krakow.
Enamelware.
A pot maker.
How old are you, mother?
You are not the only
industrialist who needs labour,
Herr Schindler.
I remember earlier this
year, IG Farben ordered
a trainload of Hungarians
for its chemical factory.
The train came in through the archway
and the officer in charge of the
selection went immediately to work
and sent 2,000 of them
straight away to Special Treatment.
It is not my task to interfere with
the processes that
take place down here.
Why do you think I can help you
if I can't help IG Farben?
Allow me to express the reason.
I'm not making any judgement about you.
It's just that I know that
in the coming months,
we're all going to
need portable wealth.
I could have you arrested.
I'm protected by powerful friends.
You should know that.
I do not say I am accepting them.
All I say is, I'm not comfortable
with them on the table.
I have a shipment coming in tomorrow.
I'll cut you 300 units from it.
New ones.
These are fresh.
The train comes, we turn it around.
Mmm, yes, yes.
-It's yours.
-I understand.
I want these.
You shouldn't get stuck on names.
That's right.
It creates a lot of paperwork.
Zoldinger, Ernestina!
Waldergrun, Hilda!
Waldergrun, Leonora!
Laast, Anna!
Pfefferberg, Mila!
Dresner, Horsch!
Dresner, Danka!
Nussbaum, Sidonia!
Rosner, Manci!
Hirsch, Helen!
Grosz, Chaja Sara!
Seelenfreund, Estella!
Schneller laufen!
(Run faster!)
Schneller laufen! Schneller!
(Run faster! Faster!)
Schneller! Schneller! Mach schon! Voran!
(Faster! Faster! Come on! Forward!)
Los, los, los! Schneller!
(Go, go, go! Faster!)
Schneller! Bewegt euch!
(Faster! Move!)
Bojcie sie! Bojcie sie!
(Scare them! Scare them!)
No! No! No!
Madchen, los jetzt aber! Jetzt aber Tempo!
(Girl, let's go now! Now, quickly!)
Danka! Danka! Danka!
No! No! No!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
These are mine! These are my workers!
They should be on my train!
They're skilled munitions workers!
They're essential!
Essential girls!
Their fingers polish the insides
of shell metal casings.
How else am I to polish the inside
of a 45 millimetre shell casing?
You tell me. You tell me!
Back on the train!
Under Department 'W' provisions
it is unlawful to kill a
worker without just cause.
Under the Businesses Compensation Fund
I am entitled to file damage
claims for such deaths.
If you shoot without thinking,
you go to prison,
I get paid.
That's how it works.
So,
there will be no summary
executions here.
There will be no interference
of any kind with production.
In hopes of ensuring that,
guards will no longer be
allowed on the factory floor
without my authorization.
For your cooperation,
you have my gratitude.
Come on, come.
Mensch, seit Jahren hab ich so etwas nicht mehr gesehen.
(Men, I have not had such a thing for years).
Come on, boys, come.
Guck dir mal die Buddeln an!
(Look at the men!)
No doorman
or maitre d' will ever
mistake you again.
I promise.
Itzhak.
This is Itzhak Stern, my accountant.
Itzhak...
You must be Mrs. Schindler.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Emilie has volunteered
to work in the clinic.
-Very generous of you.
-I know.
We need to talk when you have a moment.
This is my wife, Stern. I don't
keep any secrets from my spouse.
Oskar, please, attend to business.
It's much more attractive.
Madam.
Hello.
-What is it?
-We've received an angry complaint
from the Armaments Board.
The artillery shells,
tank shells, rocket casings,
apparently all of them have
failed quality control tests.
That's to be expected.
Start-up problems.
This isn't pots and pans.
This is a precise business.
I'll write them a letter.
They're withholding payment.
Sure, so would I, so would you.
I wouldn't worry about it. We'll
get it right one of these days.
There's a rumour you've been going
around miscalibrating the machines.
They could shut us down,
send us back to Auschwitz.
I'll call around, find out
where we can buy shells.
Pass them off as ours.
I don't see the difference.
Whether they're made here
or somewhere else...
You don't see a difference?
I see a difference.
You'll lose a lot of money.
Fewer shells will be made.
Stern, if this factory ever produces
a shell that can actually be fired,
I'll be very unhappy-
Hello, madam.
How do you do?
How are you doing, Rabbi?
Rabbi!
Good, Herr Direktor.
Sun's going down.
Yes, it is.
What day is this?
Friday?
It is Friday, isn't it?
Is it?
What's the matter with you?
You should be preparing
for the Sabbath.
Shouldn't you?
I've got some wine.
In my office. Come.
What?
Do you have any money...
hidden away some place
that I don't know about?
No.
Why? Am I broke?
Uh...
Well...
Yesterday morning,
at 2:41 a.m.,
at General Eisenhower's headquarters,
General Jodl
signed the Act of
Unconditional Surrender
of all German land,
sea and air forces in Europe
to the Allied Expeditionary Force
and simultaneously
to the Soviet High Command.
The German war is,
therefore, at an end.
But let us not forget for a moment...
I think it's time the guards
came into the factory.
Japan, with all her treachery...
The unconditional
surrender of Germany...
has just been announced.
At midnight tonight,
the war is over.
Tomorrow...
you'll begin the process of looking
for survivors of your families.
In most cases,
you won't find them.
After six long years of murder,
victims are being mourned
throughout the world.
We've survived.
Many of you have come up to me
and thanked me.
Thank yourselves.
Thank your fearless Stern
and others among you
who worried about you
and faced death at every moment.
I'm a member of the Nazi Party.
I'm a munitions manufacturer.
I'm a profiteer of slave labour.
I am...
a criminal.
At midnight you'll be free,
and I'll be hunted.
I shall remain with you until
five minutes after midnight,
after which time,
and I hope you'll forgive me,
I have to flee.
I know you have received
orders from our commandant,
which he has received
from his superiors,
to dispose of the population
of this camp.
Now would be the time to do it.
Here they are, they're all here.
This is your opportunity.
Or you could leave
and return to your families as men
instead of murderers.
In memory of the countless
victims among your people,
I ask us to observe
three minutes of silence.
Thank you, Mr. Jereth.
Open wide.
As soon as peace occurs, I want...
I want that cloth
distributed to the workers.
Two and a half meters each.
Also, each person is to
get a bottle of vodka.
They won't drink it.
They know its value.
Likewise those Egipshi
cigarettes we organized.
It'll be done.
Everything you ask.
We've written a letter,
trying to explain things
in case you are captured.
Every worker has signed it.
Thank you.
It is Hebrew, from the Talmud.
It says, 'Whoever saves one
life, saves the world entire.'
I could have got more out.
I could have got more.
I don't know.
If I just...
I could have got more.
Oskar, there are 1,100 people who are
alive because of you. Look at them.
If I'd made more money.
I threw away so much money.
You have no idea.
If I had just...
There will be generations
because of what you did.
I didn't do enough.
You did so much.
This car.
Goeth would've bought this car.
Why did I keep the car?
Ten people right there.
Ten people.
Ten more people.
This pin...
Two people.
This is gold.
Two more people.
He would have given me
two for it, at least one.
He would have given me one, one more.
One more person.
A person, Stern.
For this.
I could have gotten
one more person,
and I didn't.
And I didn't!
You have been liberated
by the Soviet Army!
Have you been in Poland?
I just came from Poland.
Are there any Jews left?
Where should we go?
Don't go east, that's for sure.
They hate you there.
I wouldn't go west either,
if I were you.
We could use some food.
Isn't there a town over there?
Heil Hitler.