
1
00:01:16,413 --> 00:01:22,669
CITY LIGHTS

2
00:01:33,471 --> 00:01:39,227
"To the people of this city we donate this
monument; 'Peace and Prosperity'."

3
00:04:40,158 --> 00:04:42,452
Afternoon.

4
00:07:59,399 --> 00:08:02,736
"Did you pick it up, sir?"

5
00:08:45,779 --> 00:08:48,948
"Wait for your change, sir."

6
00:09:49,235 --> 00:09:52,030
Evening.

7
00:10:13,175 --> 00:10:14,594
"Grandma."

8
00:11:12,276 --> 00:11:14,528
Night.

9
00:12:34,717 --> 00:12:38,637
"Tomorrow the birds will sing."

10
00:12:46,479 --> 00:12:48,856
"Be brave! Face life!"

11
00:12:56,947 --> 00:12:59,325
"No, I'll end it all!"

12
00:14:46,557 --> 00:14:50,728
"I'm cured. You're
my friend for life."

13
00:15:17,546 --> 00:15:21,384
"We'll go home and
get warmed up."

14
00:16:12,852 --> 00:16:14,228
"Any news?"

15
00:16:17,481 --> 00:16:22,111
"Only that your wife
sent for her baggage, sir."

16
00:16:23,779 --> 00:16:24,739
"Good!"

17
00:16:47,595 --> 00:16:50,139
"Here's to our friendship --"

18
00:20:02,289 --> 00:20:04,041
"No, I'll live!"

19
00:20:13,926 --> 00:20:15,553
"James - The Rolls - Royce. We'll burn up the town!"

20
00:26:47,903 --> 00:26:52,241
Early morning;
homeward bound.

21
00:27:33,167 --> 00:27:36,152
"Be careful how
you're driving."

22
00:27:38,454 --> 00:27:40,539
"Am I driving?"

23
00:28:11,145 --> 00:28:13,988
"I like your car."

24
00:28:16,025 --> 00:28:19,000
"Then keep it, it's yours."

25
00:29:25,987 --> 00:29:27,947
"Where's my friend?"

26
00:29:31,742 --> 00:29:35,163
"Let him in, he's my guest!"

27
00:29:52,597 --> 00:29:55,224
"Let's buy some flowers."

28
00:30:30,009 --> 00:30:32,136
"Here's ten dollars."

29
00:30:34,055 --> 00:30:36,516
"I haven't any change, sir."

30
00:31:14,637 --> 00:31:18,474
"Take these inside;
I'll be right back."

31
00:32:13,813 --> 00:32:17,192
"Thank you for your kindness, sir."

32
00:32:36,544 --> 00:32:39,672
"May I see you home again?"

33
00:32:42,133 --> 00:32:44,511
"Whenever you wish, sir."

34
00:33:52,537 --> 00:33:57,751
The sober dawn
awakens a different man.

35
00:34:38,416 --> 00:34:41,294
"I'm out to everybody!"

36
00:34:55,433 --> 00:34:59,270
"Whoever he is,
get rid of him!"

37
00:37:03,103 --> 00:37:07,190
"-- And then he brought me
home in his car."

38
00:37:10,819 --> 00:37:13,113
"He must be wealthy."

39
00:37:17,075 --> 00:37:19,953
"Yes, but he's more than that."

40
00:37:26,226 --> 00:37:29,146
That afternoon.

41
00:37:52,127 --> 00:37:53,670
"My friend!"

42
00:37:58,383 --> 00:38:02,721
"Come on home, I'll
give you a swell party."

43
00:38:28,622 --> 00:38:30,207
The party.

44
00:41:48,238 --> 00:41:50,991
The morning after.

45
00:43:44,396 --> 00:43:47,899
"I'm sailing at noon, so hurry!"

46
00:45:23,411 --> 00:45:24,746
"She has a fever and needs careful attention."

47
00:45:48,537 --> 00:45:53,901
Determined to help
the girl, he found work.

48
00:47:00,641 --> 00:47:05,311
FINAL NOTICE
Madam: You are owing $22. 00 rent.

49
00:47:05,645 --> 00:47:09,231
Unless paid by tomorrow morning,

50
00:47:09,440 --> 00:47:11,275
we shall take possession.

51
00:47:39,471 --> 00:47:42,433
"Grandma, he's coming today!"

52
00:47:53,611 --> 00:47:55,988
"Grandma, what's wrong?"

53
00:48:22,239 --> 00:48:26,076
"Grandma, I wish you'd meet him;

54
00:48:26,285 --> 00:48:28,829
you're never here when he calls."

55
00:48:46,520 --> 00:48:48,249
Lunch time.

56
00:49:48,934 --> 00:49:51,604
"Have you seen the soap?"

57
00:50:26,055 --> 00:50:28,182
"Be back on time!"

58
00:50:39,026 --> 00:50:44,073
"To play the part of a gentleman
without the millionaire was difficult,

59
00:50:44,281 --> 00:50:47,891
but he did his best."

60
00:51:42,628 --> 00:51:43,000
VIENNA DOCTOR HAS
CURE FOR BLINDNESS

61
00:51:43,001 --> 00:51:44,000
Thousands journey from
all parts of the world.

62
00:51:44,001 --> 00:51:44,497
FREE OPERATION FOR POOR

63
00:51:44,499 --> 00:51:45,497
Miraculous Work Of Surgeon
Astounds Medical Profession

64
00:51:50,181 --> 00:51:54,018
"Wonderful! Then I'll
be able to see you."

65
00:53:58,742 --> 00:54:01,437
"For me? Read it please."

66
00:54:07,755 --> 00:54:09,284
FINAL NOTICE
Madam: You are owing $22. 00 rent.

67
00:54:10,377 --> 00:54:15,076
Unless paid by tomorrow morning,
we shall take possession.

68
00:54:40,768 --> 00:54:45,648
"Now don't worry, I'll pay it
the first thing in the morning."

69
00:55:10,381 --> 00:55:11,632
Late.

70
00:55:21,058 --> 00:55:24,228
"You're late for the last time!"

71
00:55:36,240 --> 00:55:37,616
"Get out!!!"

72
00:55:55,134 --> 00:55:59,054
"Do you want to make
some easy money?"

73
00:56:09,000 --> 00:56:12,018
That night.

74
00:56:50,958 --> 00:56:54,301
"Remember, we split fifty - Fifty;
and you promise you won't hurt me."

75
00:56:54,510 --> 00:56:58,263
"Be careful, the boss
might hear us."

76
00:57:53,736 --> 00:57:56,572
TELEGRAM

77
00:57:56,780 --> 00:58:00,200
EDDIE MASON
MAIN STREET ARENA

78
00:58:00,300 --> 00:58:00,600
GET OUT OF TOWN
THE COPS ARE AFTER YOU

79
00:58:00,700 --> 00:58:01,200
JIM

80
00:58:16,575 --> 00:58:19,578
"I've got to beat it; boss!"

81
00:58:35,761 --> 00:58:39,515
"Do you want to fight
for a fifty dollar purse?"

82
00:58:39,765 --> 00:58:42,142
Winner take all.

83
00:58:54,196 --> 00:58:56,323
"You'll fight him!"

84
01:00:04,099 --> 01:00:07,728
"That's my lucky
rabbit's foot."

85
01:01:35,482 --> 01:01:40,195
"Let's take it easy and
we'll split fifty - Fifty."

86
01:01:44,700 --> 01:01:46,618
"Winner take all!"

87
01:09:25,369 --> 01:09:29,414
Still hoping to get
money for the girl,

88
01:09:29,623 --> 01:09:31,834
he wandered the city.

89
01:09:54,273 --> 01:09:56,191
Back from Europe.

90
01:11:35,290 --> 01:11:40,838
"Now don't worry about
the girl, I'll take care of her."

91
01:11:53,433 --> 01:11:56,937
"Will a thousand
dollars be enough?"

92
01:13:54,129 --> 01:13:55,672
"Police! Help!!"

93
01:14:37,506 --> 01:14:41,593
"He has been robbed,
search that man!"

94
01:15:20,257 --> 01:15:23,510
"Where did you get this money?"

95
01:15:32,436 --> 01:15:36,106
"Tell him you gave
me that money."

96
01:15:46,408 --> 01:15:48,952
"Who is this man?"

97
01:17:08,907 --> 01:17:11,452
"This is for the rent."

98
01:17:16,915 --> 01:17:19,918
"And this is for your eyes."

99
01:18:08,383 --> 01:18:10,844
"I must be going."

100
01:18:16,809 --> 01:18:19,770
"How can I ever thank you?"

101
01:18:40,582 --> 01:18:42,960
"You're not going away?"

102
01:18:46,630 --> 01:18:47,798
"For awhile."

103
01:18:49,925 --> 01:18:52,553
"But you're coming back!"

104
01:20:03,949 --> 01:20:06,643
Autumn.

105
01:21:24,329 --> 01:21:27,291
"I'd like to order
some flowers."

106
01:21:39,970 --> 01:21:43,223
"Why, what's the
matter, child?"

107
01:21:45,142 --> 01:21:49,605
"Nothing, only I
thought he had returned."

108
01:23:47,306 --> 01:23:50,059
"I've made a conquest!"

109
01:25:14,560 --> 01:25:16,353
"You?"

110
01:25:24,903 --> 01:25:27,030
"You can see now?"

111
01:25:33,871 --> 01:25:36,582
"Yes, I can see now."

112
01:25:53,864 --> 01:25:58,562
THE END


